[MUSIC]
Stanford University.
>> Okay, welcome to Lecture Number 11 of
欢迎来到斯坦福大学 2015 年冬季 CS193P
Stanford CS193P Winter 2015.
第 11 课
And today, we have a few topics to talk about.
今天我们将会聊到几个话题
I'm gonna start off by talking to you about your final
我会从你们的最终项目要求讲起
project requirements.
You know?
All the details of what you need to do, and by when.
你们需要做什么，什么时候完成等等一切细节
Then we're gonna go over some topics briefly.
然后我们会短暂地带过一些主题
I'll get through as many of these as I
我将会在这段时间中讲尽可能多的内容
can fit the time of.
I might not, especially, the last one,
特别是这个，最后这个，
probably won't get to.
我或许不会讲到，
But that's okay, I'll just start off the lecture next
但没关系，下一周我会继续讲
week because we don't have lecture on Monday.
因为周一我们没有课
So next Wednesday will be our next lecture.
那么下个星期三就是我们下一次课程
All right, so start right into these
好了，进入我们
final project requirements and feel free to stop and ask me
最终项目的要求讲解，如果我没说清楚，或者你有不明白的地方
questions if I say something or you don't understand it.
大家可以在任何时候问我
We ask everyone to submit a proposal for
对于接下来我们要做的事，
what they're going to do.
我会让大家提交一个提议
And it's a simple proposal,
一个很简单的申请
I am going to show you a sample proposal in a minute or
我马上会给你看一个简单的申请
two so you can get an idea of what a proposal looks like.
这样你就知道一个申请到底是指什么
Proposals, and please submit them in PDF format only,
这个申请，请大家使用 PDF 格式的文件提交
not just sending them in an email or in Word format or
不要只是通过 email 或者 Wrod 格式
something like that.
之类的东西发送
Please, PDF.
PDF，谢谢
And the proposal,
这个申请
really you can have two big sections in it.
需要有两个模块在其中
One is what you're doing, obviously, and
当然了，第一，你要干嘛
then another one is what parts of iOS you're going to use.
另一个模块就是列出你将会使用 iOS 中什么模块
And again I'm gonna show you
我马上就会给你展示
an example of that in a second.
一个例子
The project is going to be due on Friday the 13th.
这个项目需要在13号星期五之前提交
[SOUND] Be ready for that, midnight on that day,
准备好，在那一天的午夜之前
Pacific Time, yes.
太平洋时间，当然了
Use the normal submission process,
使用通常的提交流程
there'll be an option in there for the final project.
在最终项目中会有一个注意事项
You can't use any free late days.
你不能使用延迟提交的权利
We're already totally pushing this out to as late as we can
我们已经把这个时间推迟到了
and still get them all graded and
刚好能够提交成绩的时间
by the time we have to get the grades submitted.
到了时间我们就会提交所有的成绩
So lateness is very highly penalized.
所以晚交作业的后果是很严重的
Basically one letter grade per day
迟交一天降低一个字母等级
because we just can't afford it to be late.
我们确实不能承担晚交的后果了
Okay? So
好吗？
if you have any free late days late
如果你有任何延迟时间
use them on assignments four and
请在作业四或者
five because you cannot use them on the final project.
作业五阶段使用，因为你不能在最终项目中使用了
I can't grant extensions.
我不会允许延迟
There's just really no time for extensions.
已经没有时间延迟了
So basically submit whatever you have on Friday the 13th
总的来说，你必须在十三号星期五提交
and see what happens.
然后等待结果
If you don't like Friday the 13th,
如果你不喜欢十三号的周五（黑色星期五）
you can submit in on the 12th, that'd be fine.
那你可以在十二号提交，这样也可以
This is a three week-long project, right?
这是一个为期三周的项目
It's not due until, basically what, four and
从现在到提交的时间，有大概，四到
a half weeks from today.
四周半的样子
But you need a week to think about what you're gonna do.
但你需要一周的时间来思考你要怎么做
You still have a couple of assignments left.
你还有几个作业需要做
So it's basically a three week-long project.
所以这就是一个三周时长的项目
So even though last minute if you're in an emergency it
即使在最后一秒你有紧急情况
should hurt you too bad.
那也应该是你受伤得非常严重才行
So plan accordingly.
所以做好规划
Start early and try to get it done early.
早点开始，并且尝试着尽快结束
That way, if you have a problems,
这样的话，即使你遇到了问题
you'll have time to go track things down.
你仍然有时间去究根结底
If you don't start until the last week of the three week
如果你直到第三周的最后一周才开始
project, your project's not going to turn out that good.
我可以保证，
I can pretty much guarantee that.
你的项目质量不会太好
People often ask,
同学们总是问
can we work in teams on this final project?
我们可以组队完成最终项目吗？
And the answer is generally no, but
通常这个答案是 —— 不
I do allow teams of two only
但我确实会允许两人组队
in these very specific circumstances here: Both
在这种特定的情况下
students have to be taking the course passment credit.
当两个学生必须拥有足够的学分
The homework grades for both students have to be
并且两个学生在作业分数上
substantially similar and good.
要水平相当
No team can consist of anyone who's
不允许有队伍中存在着
basically been struggling in the course so far.
其中一个学生一直在这门课程中挣扎的情况
You have to submit a proposal and
你必须提交申请
your proposal has to be explicitly approved.
你的申请需要被明确地批准才行
The rest of you are going to submit a proposal and
其余的人都需要提交申请并且
we're going to give you feedback on it.
我们会给你反馈
But there's no process whereby we have to say yes this is
这没有一个标准告诉你
approved, now go forward.
我们是如何批准的
You're just gonna get feedback.
你只会获得反馈
But if you're doing the team of two,
但如果你要成立两人小组
you do have to get it explicitly approved.
那么你必须要得到明确的批准才行
And of course, that proposal would have to cover six weeks
当然了，这个申请必须包含六周的工时
of homework time worth of work because there's two of you.
毕竟有两个人
Okay? So, that's twice as
清楚了吗？
much in there.
这是两倍的时间
The proposal also not only is gonna have to show the things
这个申请不仅需要包含
I'm gonna talk about later but
我接下来会讲到的东西
it also has to include who's gonna do what.
并且要包含谁要做什么
And I really strongly encourage you to break up
并且我强烈建议你分开
the work that's going to be happening among two people
两个人的工作的
along class boundaries.
类的边界
So, this class is being written by Joe, and
比如这个类由 Joe 完成
this class is being written by Jane.
这个类由 Jane 完成
Okay? So it's very clear who's doing
这样非常清晰地表明谁将会做什么
what, as opposed to oh, we worked together on this.
而不是相反，让我们共同完成这个。
And then it's hard for us to tell who actually understands
而且这样对于我们来说也很难分清楚
what in here, okay?
到底谁才弄明白了
Then when you submit your code,
然后当你提交代码的时候
you have to follow that up with a clear delineation,
必须伴有清晰的解释
this person did this, this person did that.
这个人做了这个，这个人做了那个
And again hopefully, that this class was written by this
并且希望大家注明，这个类是由这个人完成
person, this class was was written by that person.
那个类是由另一个人完成
So we don't end up with very many teams of two every
这样，由于我们严格的要求
quarter, because of these strict requirements.
应该也不会有太多人组队了吧
But if you wanna try and give it a try, you want to submit
如果你仍然想要尝试一下
your proposal as soon as you can put it together,
那么请尽快提交你们的申请
like in the next couple days.
比如接下来的几天
And start getting your grader to give you feedback
我们会尽快根据你的等级来给你反馈
on it as soon as possible so you can iterate and
这样你就可以尽快地思考
make sure that you have something that's workable.
确保你有值得做的东西
Okay?
好吗？
Otherwise, I strongly recommend kind of
否则，我强烈推荐
individual work.
独立工作
I mean, this course is about learning to be an iOS
我的意思是，这堂课程是关于学习如何成为 iOS 开发者的
developer and if you want us to be able to measure your
如果你想要我们正确地衡量你是否合格
success at that learning process, it's individual work.
那就独立工作
Okay? Now, understand that when
好吗？但要知道当你终将要
you go out into the real world,
进入现实社会
programming is never individual work.
编程从来不是独立工作
It's almost, I mean, 5% of what's going on in the world,
大多数情况下，我的意思是，可能有5%的情况下，
programming wise, is some individual work, okay?
会需要你独立工作
95%, you're working in teams.
另外95%的情况下，你会团队协作
And I wish I had more than ten weeks so
我希望我多出十周的时间
we could work on working in teams.
这样我们可以以团队的形式工作
But we just don't have time for that, unfortunately.
但不幸的是，我们确实没有那么多时间
All right?
好吗？
You'll be graded based on your proper use of the iOS SD case.
你的成绩会根据你使用 iOS SDK 的熟练程度
So don't hack.
所以不要使用 Hack 的方式
Okay? Make sure you understand.
好吗？确保你弄懂了
You read the documentation of the classes you're using and
你需要阅读使用的类的相关文档
you use them properly.
确保正确使用
The other thing I'm gonna say is that breadth is very,
另外我要说，广度非常
very important.
非常重要
Breadth meaning show me as much of the iOS API as you
广度意味着你要尽可能地向我展示你会的 iOS API
can, rather than going really really deep and
而不是针对某一个方面做得非常深入
doing one thing really, really, really well.
非常非常好
Some people are graphics wizes and
有的同学擅长图形学
they go do these incredible graphics apps.
他们做的那些图形应用非常棒
And I say to them well,
但我对他们说
if this had been a graphics course,
如果这是图形学课程
you'd have gotten an A plus.
那么你会得到一个 A+ 的成绩
But unfortunately, it's an iOS Development course, and
但不幸的是，这是 iOS 开发课程
you didn't show me much iOS.
而你没有向我展示足够多的 iOS 相关内容
You just showed me only the graphics part.
你只向我展示了图形学相关的部分
I don't know whether you can do table views and
我不知道你是否会使用 table views
all these other things.
或者其他的东西
What's going on?
到底怎么回事？
So breadth is extremely important.
所以，广度极其重要
It's probably the most important.
或许这是最重要的部分
And then the second thing is we're gonna ask you to do one
第二重要的是，我们会要求你做一个
significant feature that I did not teach in lecture.
很重要的功能，而我没有在课堂上教过
And that's because iOS is huge.
这是由于 iOS 非常庞大
I only teach the tiniest little fraction of it.
我只能教授极其小的一部分
I really just teach things that teach you the concepts
我是教了你一些概念而已
you need to learn other things in iOS.
你需要学习 iOS 的其他方面
So you really need to show that you can go to
所以你需要展示你可以利用好文档
the documentation, go on the internet,
利用好互联网
figure out how to do something substantial on iOS without me
弄明白如何做一些重要的模块
basically showing you and giving you a demo of it, etc.
在没有我向你展示，或者给你 demo 的情况下
So I put them in yellow there because those are really
这也是为什么我把这些标记为黄色
the two most important things to get right.
这两项是最为重要的事情
You don't wanna get stuck down a rat hole, where you
你一定不想白费功夫
just spend two of your three weeks kind of chasing after
花费两周的时间去费力追赶
one thing that never really pans out and
那些并不是很重要的事情
now you only have a week left to do a lot of breadth.
而你只有一周的时间来扩展广度
So if you start doing something and you're just
如果你开始做某个你非常喜欢的东西，但你的表现为
like, God I completely don't understand this or
啊，我完全不知道这个东西到底
I can't figure this out.
是怎么弄的
Just cut and run.
那就直接丢弃
Go pick something else,
去重新选一个
some other feature you can put in your application instead.
选择另外你可以放在应用中的功能
Notice that I don't say anything here that
注意我并不是说
you're going to be graded on how cool your app is.
你会因为你的应用有多酷而得到高分
Or how ready for the app store it is, or
或者已经在 app store 中准备得如何了
how much money it's going to make.
或者这个应用将会赚多少钱
None of those things are part of the requirements.
这些并不是要求中的一部分
This is an academic course,
这是一门学术课程
you're trying to show me your iOS capabilities.
你要向我展示你的 iOS 开发能力
That's the number one requirement, okay?
这才是最主要的标准，好吗？
Now, if after this course you want to then
如果在这门课结束后你想要那样做
take some features out maybe that you threw in just to show
那就拿出那些那些你只是向我展示你知道
me that you knew how to do something in iOS.
如何在 iOS 中完成的功能
Or if you wanna add some features because
或者你想要加入一些功能
there was something too complicated to do through.
因为那样才是完整的流程
Hey, that and more power to you.
嘿，那都是你的权利
Many, many final projects have
有许多许多的最终项目
eventually ended up on the App Store.
最后都提交到了 App Store 上
But that is nothing to do with the requirements.
但并没有符合要求
Not even, you know,
一点也没有
mention this part of what you're supposed to do.
你知道，应该做的部分
Okay, I don't even care about that.
我完全不在乎那些
Okay? The scope of the project,
这个项目的完成范围
like how much work it is.
比如能够完成多少工作
It should be three weeks of homework worth of work.
应该在三周作业工作量的范围内
Especially three of the last weeks of homework, because
特别是这最后三周的作业
you're supposed to know iOS by the end of this quarter.
你应该知道 iOS 在这个季度结束
So if you took, take a combination of assignment
如果你合理地完成了作业
three, four, and five which is the graphing calculator, and
三，四，五 也就是图形计算器
then the smash tag that you're working on now, and
然后你正在做的「smash tag」
there's gonna be an animation base thing,
而且接下来还有动画相关的内容
you take that much worth of homework work,
如果你完成了所有的家庭作业
that's about how much your final project should be.
那就是你的最终作业
Okay, maybe even slightly more because some of the stuff that
好吧，或许更多一点
you're gonna put in your final project,
那你将会安稳度过你的最终项目
you already know how to do it in the assignments.
你已经知道怎么完成要求
So it should be easy peasy for you, 'kay?
这对你来说是很简单的
Just a reminder that everyone pass no credit or
只要记得，你不会得到学分和成绩
letter grade you have to pass both the homework and
除非你完成了家庭作业
the final projects separately.
和最终项目
At Stanford a passing grade is a c minus or better, 'kay?
在斯坦福及格等级是 C- 或者更好
So we will tell you if you have not passed the homework
我们会告诉你是否通过了家庭作业的考核
portion once we've finished grading homework assignment
当我们完成了作业任务的评分
five, 'kay?
好吗？
So then you can just stop work on the final project at that
如果你没有，那你也不需要完成最终项目了
point, all right?
好吗？
[SOUND].
>> [LAUGH]. >> Well,
you can keep working on it if you want, but you're not gonna
好啦，只要你想，你可以继续做
pass the course if you don't pass that part, okay?
但你不会通过这门课，如果你没有通过作业部分
'Kay, question about the scope?
对于这部分有问题吗？
Scope is important.
这部分非常重要
It's one of the things people fall down on.
这也是许多人失败了的原因
They basically submit something that's kinda
他们只是提交了大概
two weeks of work, and so two weeks of work,
两周的成果
that's two-thirds of the, for total points.
那就只有三分之二的成绩
That's not a very good grade, so
这不是非常好成绩
you wanna make sure you get your scope right there.
如果你想要确保你的成绩正确
[SOUND] Do not just regurgitate your homework
那就不要只是简单地完成你的家庭作业好吗？
assignments, okay?
I do not want to see smash tag too, okay?
我不想看到「smash tag」
And every quarter it seems like I always get a handful of
每一个季度我都会收到很多人的作业
people who can't really think of something to do so
他们完全想不到应该做什么
they basically just take smash tag or maybe the last homework
所以只是把「smash tag」
assignment and they just kinda change the names and,
或者只是把最后一个作业修改了一下名字
you know, it's very, very similar.
你懂的，非常非常相似
Don't do that, okay?
请别这样做，好吗？
Cuz then you'll have just shown us that you already what
那样就是你在向我们重复展示你
you've already shown us,
之前在家庭作业中
which is you know how to do the homework.
已经展示过的东西
Okay, great, we already, yeah, know how to do the homework.
好吗？ 我们已经知道你懂家庭作业怎么做的了
Now show us different.
请向我们展示一些不一样的东西
Basically one thing to think about is you wannna start your
基本上你需要从草图开始
final project from scratch.
思考你的最终项目
You don't wanna start it with Smashtag and
你不会想要从「smashtag」开始
then start changing it or with assignment five and
然后修改添加任务五
then start changing it or with a calculator and
或者是从修改一个计算器开始
then just start changing it.
Start from scratch, 'kay, that will help emphasize
从零开始，这样才会加强印象
you don't wanna just turn in a regurgitation of the homework
你不会想要只是重复家庭作业任务的
assignment and in fact,
而事实上
whatever you do in your final project, try to do things
无论你要在最终项目中做什么
a little differently than we did them in the assignments.
尝试着做一点与之前作业不一样的东西
Cuz if you do something exactly the same way we
因为你做了与作业相同的时，
did it in the assignment, like if you had a table view, and
比如你有一个 table view
if data structure is exactly the way we did it for
然后数据结构与我们之前完成的作业一样
the assignment, it's kinda like, well,
这就像
we already knew they could do that, so don't do that, 'kay.
我们已经知道这些东西可以做什么了
Pick a different instructor, something more interesting,
选择不同的控件，其他有趣的东西
do a couple more features in table view,
在 table view 中多尝试一些功能
do things that are maybe extra credit in the homework,
做稍微超出家庭作业的东西
do those in your final project, those kinda things to
在你的最终项目中这样做
get some difference between your homework.
与你的家庭作业区分开来
>> But, I guess I'm afraid that, how do I know what's,
>> 但，我怎么知道
you know, different, and what's like a hack,
>> 区别，比如什么是 hack
like if I make my priority the structure, like a linguist,
>> 我对结构进行优先级排列就像语言学家那样
for example, is that like a hack?
>> 这样属于 hack 吗？
Or is that okay to use?
或者说可以这样用吗？
>> Okay, so the question is,
问题是
how do I know, if I do something different than what
我怎么知道，我做的东西是否不同于
was talked about in lecture,
我们在课堂中接触到的东西
if I'm not now doing hackery, okay?
如果我不是，那属于 hack 吗？
And the answer is, well,
好吧，答案是
you're going to have to figure that out,
你需要弄明白界限
because when you go out into the real world and
因为当你在现实世界中，
build iOS apps, you need to not be a hacker, and the way
创建 iOS 应用时，你要避免成为一个 hacker
you figure those things out is by reading the documentation.
你需要通过阅读文档来弄明白这些东西
If you read the documentation of a method and it says,
如果你在文档中读到某个方法
this method works this way, and
是这样使用的
you use it that way, then you're not hacking, okay?
你也是这样使用的，那么你就不是在 hack
If you go out on the internet, and it says, oh,
如果你在网上搜到某个方法，上面写，哦
you can call this private method with this thing and
你可以调用这个私有方法，它会解决问题
it'll work, then now you're staring to hack, right?
那么你就是在 hack，好吗？
Or if you just don't read the documentation and
或者你没有阅读文档
just start typing things in until they work, okay?
并且只是在码字直到解决问题
I used to have a great GIF, I don't have it now, where it's
我以前有个很棒的 GIF 动画，现在没有了
just this GIF of this guy just banging on the keyboard and
这个 GIF 显示的这个男人在用头撞击键盘
then banging his head until he's just a bloody mess, and
直到血肉横飞
that's a programming approach that doesn't scale very well.
这种编程方法就不太好
So, you know, you'll know if you're hacking,
所以，你会知道的，你会知道你在 hack
it'll be clear.
这界限非常清楚
You can always ask your TAs, there'll still be office hours
你也可以询问你的 TA，接下来的季度中
all for the rest of the quarter, you can, you know,
的所有工作时间他们都会在，你可以
go find out if you're hacking.
去询问他们，你是否在 hack
All right, so some examples of bad projects,
好了，这就是在项目中出现的坏的例子
we already talked about Smashtag two,
我们已经谈过了「Smashtag」
that's a bad project.
那也是一个糟糕的项目
Another bad project is one that has very little breadth,
另一种糟糕的项目是只有一点点广度
like it's lots of MVCs being segued to each other but
比如有很多的 MVC 结构在其中
all the MVCs are basically the same.
但所有的 MVC 几乎都是一样的
A bunch of buttons and text fields and labels and
一大堆按钮，输入框，文本框
that's it, there's no table views in there,
没了，没有列表
there's no animation, there's no custom view with drawRect,
没有动画效果，没有使用了 drawRect 的自定义视图
you see what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思了吗？
It's all just the same thing over and over or
这就是不停地重复
vice versa with the table views.
反之亦然，列表
It's table view, after table view, after table view,
这个页面是列表，然后又是列表，又是列表
after table view, and there's nothing else,
又是列表，其他什么也没有
just table views.
就只是列表
That's all that's in it, the whole app is table views.
这就是所有的东西，整个应用就是一堆列表
Those are bad apps.
这些就属于糟糕的应用
An animated game, like you're doing a game that's all video
一个动效游戏，就像你玩的那些电视游戏一样
game, a guy running around and shooting bullets and all that
一个男人在那跑来跑去，不停地射击
stuff, that's bad too, because where's the table views?
永远都这样，这也很糟糕，因为列表在哪去了？
And it shows me that you know the animation stuff, great!
你向我展示你知道动画效果，很好
But I need to see all the rest, text fields and
但我需要看到其他的东西
labels and segues, where's that if it's just this
如果只看到一个男人在屏幕上跑跑跳跳，
one screen where the guy is running around jumping, okay.
那标签，界面跳转，这些东西哪里去了？
Another one is some cool mathematical thing or
你通过你的 PhD 研究，制作了一个与数学相关
an image filter that uses your PhD research
或者与图形处理相关
to calculate something.
的东西
That's great that you worked your PhD research in there,
你融入了你 Phd 中的研究，这样很棒
except for that's 90% or 80% of what you did, and
但如果其中90%或者80%都和那些相关
you're gonna get an F in this class,
那么你将会在这堂课上拿到一个 F
because only 20% is going to be iOS stuff.
因为只有20%的内容与 iOS 相关
You want it to be the other way around, 90% iOS and
你需要颠倒过来，要90%的内容与 iOS 相关
then you can only spend 10% of your time on doing,
然后你可以留10%的内容
putting your PhD stuff in there or
把你 Phd 相关的东西放进去
some in network resource or whatever, that's fine.
网络研究或者随便什么，都可以
The aesthetics of your UI do matter.
你对 UI 的审美同样重要
Okay, we don't want these junky,
我们不想要看到那些
totally crappy looking things but
非常糟糕的东西
I don't expect you to be graphic designers.
当然我也没有期望你变身为图形设计师
You're programmers.
你是程序员
So that just basically means,
所以，这就意味着
you know, do your auto layout nicely, line things up.
你懂的，用好 auto layout，排列整齐一点
You know, those dash blue lines help you line things
你知道的，蓝色辅助线条帮助你排列元素整齐
up so things should look nice.
这样东西会看起来好一些
Also, don't be afraid to go out on the internet,
当然了，不要害怕使用网上的资源
find some nice icon or something do in there.
找一些好看的图标或者其他的东西放进去
You're really not even gonna have to worry about,
你也不需要担心那些
do I have the rights to use this icon,
我有版权使用这个图标吗  这类的问题
because it's only for your personal work.
因为这只是你的个人项目
You're not gonna be shipping it on the App Store.
你不需要把它提交到 App Store 上去
If you do ship in the App Store,
如果你要提交到 App Store
you have to change your icons, or either buy them,
那么你就需要修改图标，或者买下那些东西
or use stuff that's free to use, all that but for this,
或者使用免费的资源，除此之外
you don't have to worry about that, so we do wanna see it.
你不需要担心这些事
By the same token this is not a human,
同样，这也不是人机
computer human interface class, okay?
人机交互课程，好吗？
So an app's not gonna be a primary thing.
对这个应用来说并不是最主要的事情
I just want to make sure you don't turn into much of junk,
我只是不希望你做出来的东西太糟糕
'kay, you wouldn't want that either.
你肯定也不希望
You're final project has to work on hardware, 'kay?
你的最终项目必须在真机上运行
And you have to demonstrate that to us.
并且你需要向我们展示
So you're gonna have a final presentation which I'm
关于最终展示，我马上会说到
gonna talk about in a second, and if you do a live demo
但只要你把最终项目的 Demo
on hardware, then you've satisfied that requirement.
运行在真机上了，那你就满足了这个要求
If you don't, then you need to show your TA,
如果你不会，那么你需要向你的 TA 展示
usually they'll hang around after the final project,
通常来说在最终项目时期他们都在
final presentation slot, or you could show it to them any
最终展示，或者你可以在此之前向他们展示
time before that, in office hours or whatever.
在工作时间或者随便什么时候
Show them your app working.
向他们展示你的成果
So that's the important part.
这是最重要的部分
You can't just be simulator only.
你不能只使用模拟器
And you're gonna notice that assignment,
注意这个要求
I don't know if I made assignment four be
我忘了是否有要求四
hardware required, I guess not, but
硬件要求，或许没有
assignment five will definitely be,
但要求五肯定会是
this must work on hardware, 'kay?
项目要能够运行在真机上
Yeah, this is kind of a reiteration of my theory four
Yeah，这可能是对于我之前要求的重申
but don't get side-tracked on non-iOS code.
不要过于专注在非 iOS 代码上
If you have something like a database that you're gonna use
如果你需要一个数据库用于登录或者什么，
or a login, a lot of people want to do a social networking
有很多人想要做一个社交网络应用
app which is great and you have to have a login,
当然如果有个登录功能是很棒的
or something like that, you know, you can fake it.
但你也可以尝试着假装
Fake the login, just have three users, and
一个假的登录，有三个默认用户账户
that's all, right?
这样就可以了
And it's some,
as long as you do it in a nice object-oriented way,
只要你面向对象完成得很好
where that faked backend is its own object somewhere, or
有一个假的后台或者其他什么东西
whatever, that's the way you wanna do it, because again,
这就是你应该做的，再说一次
you wanna focus all your time on showing me as much
你需要全力专注于向我展示
iOS usage as you can cram in there, 'kay?
你知道的 iOS 相关代码，好吗？
So if you waste a week, hooking up to a network
如果你花了一个礼拜的时间，去配置网络服务
server you've wasted a week, okay, now you have to cram
你就浪费了一周，好吗？那你就必须
three weeks of iOS programming and coding into two weeks so
把三周时间的 iOS 编程，变成只有其中两周编程
don't do that, 'kay, so be careful there.
注意不要那样做
All right, presentation,
好了，展示
this presentation I mentioned, so there's so
我之前提到过的展示
many of you this quarter, this is the max we've ever had.
这个学期有很多人，这就是我们能争取到的
Normally we have a two-minute
通常我们有两分钟的
presentation where you get up here for two minutes and
展示时间，你上去然后展示两分钟
you have to just basically tell us all about your app.
你需要简单地向我们介绍你的应用
I call it sometimes the venture capitalist pitch,
我有时候把这个称为企业资本展示
imagining a venture capitalist here, and you're trying to get
想象有一个企业家在那坐着，你要尝试着
them to invest in your company to build this app.
让他们投资你的公司来开发这款应用
You wanna put your app in the best light and show it off,
你需要用最好的灯光来展示
and you wanna show off all aspects of it, so
你要展示应用的方方面面
should give a screenshot.
展示一个好看的截屏
Do a live demo if you dare.
最好做一个 Demo
You can see I do live demos and they can be perilous.
你之前也看到我展示 Demo，这样做可能会很冒险
Somehow, you know, pitch your app to us.
使用你喜欢的方式，向我们推荐你的 App
So, unfortunately we only get 90 seconds because they're so
因为我们的学生很多，所以每个人只有90秒的时间
many of you.
We only got three hour slot and didn't really want it to
一共只有三个小时，也不想要
spill over too much into the alternate final slot.
在最终项目展示的时候超出这个时间
So 90 seconds. That doesn't seem like a long
所以90秒钟，虽然感觉不是很长的时间
time but actually you can say a lot in 90 seconds.
但实际上在这90秒内你已经可以描述很多东西了
' Kay.
If you're, if you're very focused on what
如果你有很多想要说的东西
you have to say, you can show your basically,
那么你需要在
your entire UI in about 30 seconds.
30秒内展示整个 UI
Yeah? >> [INAUDIBLE]
>> Yeah so I think I say on here.
我认为你可以这样理解
Maybe I get to second.
我有两分钟时间
The question is can I just make a video and
问题是，是否我可以做一个视频
get up here and press play?
然后上来播放
And the answer is no, 'Kay?
答案是，不
I want you guys to have the experience of standing up in
我需要你们体验站到上面来
front of your peers and having to talk to them.
面对你的同学们，向他们描述
That's a very, very important skill in your life, okay?
对于你的人生来说，这是非常非常重要的一个技能
And so you need to do that, so no pressing play, 'Kay?
所以你必须这样做，不能只是按下播放按钮
I need your slides before, because I'm going to put all
在演讲前我需要你的幻灯片，因为我会把
the slides in one big thing so we can race through this.
幻灯片放在大屏幕上，这样我们才能加快速度
Okay, we got to get to a hundred people,
我们会有上百人在这里
90 seconds each with like 10 seconds in between.
每个人有90秒钟时间，10秒的间隔时间
We're going to have to be really racing through.
所以我们需要争分夺秒
So you're gonna give me all your slides,
所以需要你给我你的幻灯片
I'm going to put them all in one gigantic presentation and
我会把它们放在一个巨大的屏幕上
we're just going to be clicking through the slides,
然后我们会浏览这些幻灯片
person after person will have any switching time.
一个接一个地切换
Please make your slides,
请做好幻灯片
you haven't noticed by now, wide screen, okay?
你还没有注意到，这里会有个大屏幕，好吗
1280x720. Do not send me 1024x768 or
1280x720，不要提交 1024x768 或者
800x600 slides.
800 x 600 的幻灯片
They will look funny, 'Kay?
这样看起来会很搞笑
The slides are due to me the day after your final
这些幻灯片可以在最终项目之后的一天提交给我
project is due, so you can get your final project in and
所以你可以先准备好你的最终项目
then spend the next day if you wanna fax, you know,
然后再隔一天时间传送给我
craft your presentation, do some screenshots or whatever.
如果你想要好好雕琢你的展示，做一些截屏什么的
Whatever you present, though, in terms of slides or
无论你想展示什么，就幻灯片或者 UI 来说
UI on that second day, should be what you turned in.
应该和你提交的一样
So don't spend Saturday adding more graphics and
所以不要在周六又向里面添加了一些图片
all that stuff and
或者其他的东西
then putting up slides that are not what your app is.
然后你的幻灯片和你提交的应用不一样
'Kay?
Your app is the presentation
你的应用就是展示
you give has to be the app you turned in.
你展示的东西必须和你提交的一样
Make sense?
有道理吧
You submit the slides also using a normal process.
同样也是通过普通流程来提交你的幻灯片
There'll be a different submit target for that,
他们会有一个不同的提交目标
final project slides, it'll be called.
叫做最终项目幻灯片
And so, yes, that's the way you do that.
好了，这就是你应该做的
Now, I know some of you have a conflict with the final exam,
我知道你们当中有的人会和期末考试有冲突
although I don't really know how that's supposed to happen,
我也不知道为什么会发生这样的事
because all the final exams are supposed to
因为期末考试之间不应该
not conflict with each other.
有冲突
But I know you guys have other things,
但我知道你们有其他的事情
you're in the GSB or something else.
你的 GSB 或者其他的课程
So I am gonna have an alternate final slot if you
所以我将会另外给你一个最终展示时间
want, which is on the very last lecture of this course.
如果你需要的话，这个时间是最后一堂课
So you can do your presentation then if
你可以在那个时候展示
you prefer.
如果你愿意的话
And there will be a sign up for that but
这将会需要登记一下
it will be really easy.
但应该会非常简单
I'll announce it on Piazza a couple weeks before.
我会提前几个星期在走廊上张贴出来
Okay?
If you do the alternate time,
如果你选择在另一个时间
obviously I need your slide sooner.
很明显我就需要你的幻灯片了提前一些
So I need them by the Monday before actually.
我需要在实际时间的周一就拿到
Now in that case, you still get to turn your stuff in
在这样的情况下，你仍然可以在周五提交
by the Friday, so you're gonna have to be making your
你的应用，也就是说你需要提前准备好
presentation out of your apps not done yet maybe.
要展示的东西，在你的应用完成之前
So, but you just gotta do the best you can if you
所以如果你想要提前展示，那就只好尽最大的努力了
wanna go early.
Okay? But presenting early has no
但提前展示不会影响
effect on when the actual thing is due.
到最终的时间
It's still due on Friday the 13th.
最终时间仍然是13号星期五
Okay?
The quality of your presentation,
关于你的演讲质量
people say oh does it matter?
有人问，哦，那个重要吗？
Yes, of course it matters.
当然重要
Okay? It matters for
这个对于你
you and your experience here at Stanford is to be giving
以及你在斯坦福的经验，这应该是一个
good presentations.
好的演讲
Does it matter to your final grade?
而且也确实会影响到你的最终成绩
Yeah, a tiny little bit.
一点点
If you come up here and you totally bomb.
如果你上来了，然后脑子一片空白
If you do a live demo and it's a complete mess,
如果你做了一个现场演示，但演讲完全就是一团糟
we're not gonna go oh, that's a B for that guy.
我们也不会噢，给这家伙一个 B
No. But, still we want,
不会的，但仍然我们希望
you can kind of impress us if you come up and
你可以让我们影响深刻，如果你上来
do a really great demo and it really shows our graph well,
然后做了一个很棒的 demo，并且也向我们展示了很好看的图片
we're more likely to walk away going wow,
我们将会表现为 Wow
that was a little better app than I thought.
这个应用或许比我想象的要好一些呢
Okay?
But, if you come up here and
但如果你上来
you're terrible, then we might be like, which app was that?
然后表现得很糟糕，我们就会表现为 这是哪个应用来着？
I thought that was terrible.
我觉得这很糟糕
Okay? So,
好吗
it matters a little because it gives us an impression, so.
这确实很重要，如果你让我们印象深刻了
And that 90 seconds is going to be strictly enforced.
然后90秒钟会是强制性限制
I'm literally going to say okay thank you,
当时间到了我会直接告诉你
right at 90 seconds cause we just can not afford to go over
好了谢谢 因为人数的关系
too many people.
我们不能延长时间
Yeah, question, should I do a live demo?
好了，问题是，是否我应该做一个现场演示
I love live demos as you can tell,
看的出来我非常喜欢现场演示
I do a live demo almost every single lecture.
几乎每一堂课我都会做现场演示
But I know that for some people, it's like, oh,
但我知道对于有的人来说，这就像
it's a little scary, it might not work,
这有点可怕，或许不会成功
especially if you're going out on the network,
特别是如果你将要使用到网络
maybe you can't get the network or something.
或许你不能连上网络或者其他的事
So, it's dangerous.
这样看起来很危险
So, what I recommend is, live demos are pretty effective,
所以，我的建议是，现场演示非常有效
so, you know, try and
你懂的，尝试一下
put a live demo together if you can but have a backup.
做一个现场演示，但如果可以的话准备好备用计划
If you get up here to do your live demo, it's like,
如果你上来准备现场演示
it won't project.
这不会部署成功
Your device won't project.
你的设备不能部署
Or the network doesn't work.
或者网络无法连接
Or you have audio and it's not working.
或者你有一个音频但没有播放
Then just switch to your Keynote.
那就直接切换到你的 Keynote
So have your Keynote slides as back up if you're gonna
让你的 Keynote 幻灯片回来
go live demo, is my recommendation, 'Kay?
这就是我推荐的方式，如果你要做现场演示的话
All right, so the proposal.
好了，申请表
Sample proposal.
申请表示例
Here I'm just gonna show you what one would look like so
我将会向你展示一下
you can kinda get an idea.
这样你就知道这到底是什么
My sample proposal is I'm gonna build a Shakespeare
我的申请表示例是我将要做一个「Shakespeare Director」
director app.
应用
So I'm a director of a Shakespearean play, and
我是莎士比亚戏剧的导演
I'm gonna have this nice iPad app to help me do that and
我需要这个 iPad app 帮助我
help my actors.
帮助我的演员
And so it's basically going to have a table for
基本上里面会有一个列表
choosing a Shakespearean play.
用来选择莎士比亚的戏剧
So you can pick a play, the one you're doing.
你可以选择其中一部，你要用的那部
And then it will let you lay out, you're the director, so
然后它会让你布局，你是导演
you're gonna lay out the blocking,
你需要对舞台进行布局
which is where everyone stands on stage,
这就是所有人站在舞台上
on a little kind of graphical stage.
在一个小的平面舞台上
So I'm gonna have a drawRect there.
我将会在这里使用 drawRect
I'm gonna have gesture, so I can move things around.
这里会用到手势，这样我才能移动这些东西
It's also gonna have a dialog learning mode,
这里会有一个台词学习模式
where it's going to show the dialog line by line
用来一行一行地展示台词
so that actors can have their own iPad maybe while they're
这样演员们可以在他们的 iPad 上
learning their lines.
学习台词
And they'll see their blocking and
与此同时，他们也能看到舞台的布局
their lines right there at the same time.
以及他们的台词
And they'll also be able to record the other people's
然后这会录下来这些人的台词
lines, so it'll prompt them.
这样可以即时的提醒他们
So that they can sit there and
这样他们就可以坐在那
learn their lines and all that.
学习台词和其他的东西
So you can see, it's a pretty cool app, right?
你可以感受到，这是一个很酷的应用对吧
It's pretty good idea.
是个很棒的点子
I'm basically explaining what it does in my proposal.
我就是在申请表中解释我将要干嘛
I'm talking about limitations, though,
我会说到限制
like I'm saying that my custom view is only going to be
比如我会说我的自定义视图只会是
rectangles and circles and I'll let them set color.
方形和圆形然后我们设置他们的颜色
So, the people are not going to be really great graphics.
所以，人不会是非常好看的图形
I'm just saying that I don't want to spend all my time
我不想花费大量的时间在
doing that, so I'm just gonna make my, when I lay
这上面，所以我只会将就做一个，当我排列好
out where everyone is on stage it's just gonna be block.
舞台上的所有人，这些人就只是方块
See? So, I'm kind
看到了吗？我在
of explaining my proposal that I realize because if I don't
解释我的申请，然后我意识到，如果我不把这个放在这
put that in here, then your TA's going to feedback and
那么你的 TA 将会给予一个反馈
say, whoa, you're gonna have this whole blocking thing?
你需要这样一个舞台的东西？
How complicated is that gonna be?
这个东西会有多复杂？
What are you gonna allow?
你需要怎么实现？
You see what I mean?
明白我的意思了吗？
So this heads that off by saying, okay,
所以只是把要做的事列出来
I understand that mostly I'm focusing on doing draw rec and
我知道大多是的情况下我需要专注于 drawRect
gestures and things like that.
手势等等
That's what I'm trying to show you with this feature.
这也是我将要向你展示的功能
But I'm saying here that I'm gonna be able to let you
但我的意思是，我允许你
take a photo of a person and put that in a rectangle so
让一张人的照片在那个方块中
that when you're blocking you can at least have
当你在布局舞台的时候，至少你可以
pictures of the people, maybe in their nice costumes.
有一些人的照片，甚至穿着好看的服装
And I'm telling you other things here, you know,
而且我将告诉你另外一件事
that sound recording sound is going to be possible.
第
第二个录音的点子几乎不可能实现
I notice that I mention that it's iPad only.
我注意到我之前说了这只是个 iPad 应用
Now, when I say iPad only there,
当我说只支持 iPad 的时候
that hurts breadth, okay?
其实就丧失了一些广度
Because an app that works on both iPhone and
因为一个应用能够在 iPhone 和 iPad
iPad has more breadth although it's pretty easy to make
运行将会拥有更大的广度，并且要让应用支持
an app that's just kinda works on both.
也非常简单
But you still have to make sure the adaptations
但你还是需要确保在旋转屏幕的时候
are working maybe and that when it rotates in both sides,
自适应功能是支持的
it does the right thing.
这样才是对的
So it's a little more work.
所以这就是多余的一点工作量
So you just lost breadth.
你也会损失广度
I lost breadth by saying, iPad only.
我在说出只支持 iPad 的时候，损失了广度
But I decided that this app just doesn't make sense
但我觉得这个应用如果没有 iPad 的话
without iPad.
就完全不合理
Although i could, I could decide that maybe the blocking
所以我就觉得，我觉得或许舞台
part is not on the iPhone version just the dialog
这个功能不应该出现在 iPhone 的版本上
warnings cause I could imagine the actors standing
当然我可以想象一群演员站在那
here with just their iPhone learning their lines or
只有他们的 iPhone 然后学习台词
whatever so I could, I could if I needed the breath,
或者，如果我愿意，我需要一点广度
I could add that back in.
那么我就把这个功能加回来
Okay, to here section one,
这个部分就这样
where I'm explaining what I'm doing.
之前就是在解释我将要做什么
Now here's section two, here's all the iOS API
现在是第二部分，这里全是 iOS API
that I'm gonna use to implement that.
我将要实现的
I'm using TableView as a custom TableView cell.
我要使用 TableView 及自定义 TableView Cell
A UIView with drawRect.
一个使用 drawRect 的 UIView
The camera.
摄像头
Popovers.
Popovers
I'm using scroll view to zoom in around in
我将会使用 ScrollView 用来缩放
the blocking view.
这个舞台
I'm using AVFoundation to do the recording of the sound.
我要使用 AVFoundation 来录音
I'm using timers.
我要使用 NSTimers
I'm gonna use a thing called Core Data, which is an object
我会使用一个叫做 Core Data 的东西，就是一个
oriented database to store my data in there.
面向对象的数据库用于存放我的数据
That would be a not covered in lecture feature,
这个不会包含在课程中
cuz we're not covering that in lecture this quarter.
因为在这学期我们不会讲到相关内容
I'm also gonna make it so
我需要使用这个这样我才能
I can print out my blocking on a printer.
在打印机上打印出我的舞台
That's also not covered in lecture [SOUND], okay?
这些东西不会包含在课程中
So there I'm doing substantial
这里我重标记了
not covering in lecture futures.
不会包含在未来的课程当中
I'm making it really care what they are in my proposal and
在我的申请里我解释得很明白了
I'm talking about all the other things I'm gonna do.
我将会说到我将会做的其他所有的东西
'Kay?
That help you understand what's going on there?
这样可以帮助你理解
Proposals.
申请表
Okay, so you submit those proposals as soon as possible,
好的，请尽快提交你们的申请表
but really no later than next Tuesday, please,
并且请尽量不要超过下周二，谢谢
to your grading TA, whoever graded your last assignment.
提交给你的打分 TA，那个给你上次任务打分的人
And they have a lot of you to read, so they'll,
他们会有很多的申请表需要处理
as quickly as they can, get some feedback to you.
当然，他们也会在最快的时间内给你反馈
If you don't give it to us by next Tuesday, you know,
如果你没有在下周二之前提交给我们
still going to be beneficial for you to send it to us.
你仍然能够从我们这里得到一些好处
It's just that there's going to be less and less time for
只是越晚就越少的时间让我们来
us to give you any feedback, and
给你任何反馈
you're going to have to already have gotten started
而且你可能已经开始了
pretty soon, by the end of next week, let's say.
在下周周末
You're probably really want to get started.
你或许非常想要开始
So it's really your own thing.
所以，这其实完全在你
And again though it's not, you don't have to get it approved
重申一次，你不需要在得到批准后
to start on your project,
再开始你的项目
unless you're the two-man team, you do.
除非你是在二人小组中
You don't have to get approval, but
你不需要获得批准
you really do wanna get that TA feedback.
但你可能会需要 TA 的反馈
Cuz you don't wanna start off on a trajectory where the TAs
因为你肯定不想从一个 TA 们觉得
are like, you're not likely to end up with much of a very
不太好的项目开始
good project here, cuz there's not gonna be enough breadth,
或许没有足够的广度
or I don't understand what your not covering lecture
或许我没有明白你是否已经把课堂中的内容
feature is, or it's not a good enough one, or whatever.
包含进去了，或者这个项目不够好，或者其他
Now, the other thing to note is that proposal is completely
另一个需要注意的是，申请表完全不是绑定的
non-binding, except for
除了
a little bit with a two-man team.
两人小组
But for everyone else, it's not really binding either way.
但对于其他的人来说，没有绑定的意思
So if what you turn in is completely
所以如果你最后提交的项目
different that your proposal, that's fine, okay?
完全不同于你的申请表，这样也可以，好吗
We're not gonna go back and say, hey wait,
我们也不会翻出你的申请表然后说
you said in your proposal you're gonna do it.
等等，你在你的申请表里面说你将会做这个
No, we will not say that.
不，我们永远不会这样说
But vice versa, too.
但相反的
If we say in your proposal,
如果我们在你的申请表里说
oh yeah, doing core data for that,
恩，就要这样使用 Core Data
that sounds like a good not covered in lecture feature.
这样听起来不错，但并没有在课堂中讲过
And then you go to implement it, and
然后你在实现的过程中
you do such a trivial version of core data that's not
你只是使用了 Core Data 的一小部分
substantive enough, we still might ding you and say hey,
并且不会产生显著的效果，我们仍然可能会提示你
that was not a substantial not covered in lecture feature.
这样并不是很有效，而且也没有包含在课程中
In other words, your proposal is not graded.
换句话说，你的申请表并不会计分
It's no part of the grade, we'll never look at it again,
这并不是成绩的一部分，我们也不会再看第二次
it's just to get you started on the right track.
这只是用于让你有一个正确的开始
You are still responsible for delivering all
你仍然需要负责实现
the requirements that I talked about today in your final
我今天提到的所有的任务要求
project, regardless of what's happening with your proposal.
无论你的申请表得到什么反馈
So it cuts both ways.
这样两方都受到制约
We won't hold it against you, and, you know, but
我们不会用来反对你，而你
you can't come back and say but you said that was okay.
你也不能回来告诉我们说，你之前说这样可以啊
All right?
好吗？
Make sense?
这样有道理吧
Okay.
Last thing I want to talk about is collaboration.
关于合作我最后说一下
So people ask me okay, but
有人问我
can I work with someone else not in this class on it?
我能否和某个不在这堂课中的人协作？
And the answer is absolutely you can,
答案是，当然可以
in fact I strongly encourage that.
事实上我非常鼓励你这样
In fact, last quarter
事实上，上个学期
I had a thing where it was a requirement
我就有个要求
to go find somebody to work with outside of this class.
就是去班级之外找一个人
When I say that, be very careful,
需要注意的是，这个人
I mean non-coding help.
我指的是非代码相关的帮助
Okay?
好吗？
You can get someone to help you like a marketing person,
你可以找一个懂市场的家伙来帮助你
or a salesperson, or somebody who is kind of
或者推销员，或者某个
a business development person, or an idea man, okay, or
属于商业开发的家伙，或者一个点子男
idea woman, who's going to give you an idea.
点子女，一个能够提供给你好的主意的人
That's fine for someone else to give you the idea.
有一个人提供想法，这样是可以的
But you've gotta totally be the coder and
但你要作为那个写代码的人
architect of the solution, okay?
并且设计出解决方案来
Because you are in an iOS development class so
因为你在 iOS 开发课程中
you gotta do the iOS development part of it, okay?
所以你需要负责 iOS 开发的部分
Now, that other person who's helping you could also help
你找来的人可以提供
you with things, maybe giving you assets,
一些帮助，给你一些资源
maybe they could give you some images or
必须他们可以给你一些图片
they might give you access to a database or something,
或者他们可以给你一些数据方面的资源
or some network server that you're gonna oh,
或许是一些你需要的网络服务
perfectly fair game.
公平的游戏
It's just they cannot help you with the actual
限制就是不能让他们来帮你
coding of your app.
写代码
And it can't be someone else in the class either.
而且这个人也不能在我们的课堂中
Okay? It's gotta be someone
好吗？这个人必须是
outside of this class.
在课堂以外的人
Okay?
So I do have two people here, two Stanford affiliates,
比如这里有两个人，两个斯坦福的人
who are going to get up and
他们在谈论
talk a little bit about what they're doing.
他们想要做的事
And if you like what they're doing,
而你很喜欢他们的想法
then you can contact them,
那么你可以联系他们
and maybe they would be your outside idea man or woman.
或许他们会是你在外部的想法来源
And you could work with with them to
你也可以和他们一起工作
understand more what they want.
知道他们到底想要什么
Now what they want might not be suitable,
他们现在想要的东西或许不适合
exactly, for a final project, because you know what
比如对于最终项目来说，因为你知道
the requirements are, you've seen them all today.
要求有那些，你今天已经看到了所有的要求
They're specific academic requirements, and
这些全都属于学术要求
you got to meet those.
你也必须达成这些要求
But by the same token, what you do,
但与此同时，你要做的
what their idea is might help guide you towards
他们的点子或者会引导你
putting together a lot of good features, and vice versa.
扩展出非常多好的功能，反之亦然
If you work with these people and
如果你和一些人工作
you find out this is great, this is really interesting
你觉得他们的想法很棒，很有意思
maybe then after the class is over you can say okay,
或许你可以在课程结束之后
well now let's work together and
再与他们合作
go do something really what we want to do,
去做一些真正有意思的东西
based the specs of what the requirements are.
而不是依照要求做的东西
That make sense?
很合理吧？
So back to learning about iOS itself.
让我们回到 iOS 的学习中
The next thing I'm going to talk about is the unwind
下一个我们要说到的东西是 unwind
segue.
segue
Now this is kind of a weird thing,
这是一个很奇怪的东西
because I talked to you about all this stuff about segues,
因为之前告诉过你们 segues 是什么
and then the unwind comes along and
现在来了个 unwind
unwinds a little bit of your knowledge about it.
unwinds 你应该知道一点点
The most important difference of an unwind segue versus all
它与你知道的那些 segues 最重要的区别就是
those other segues that you know, the show segue and
show segue 和 pop over segue
the pop over segue is that it does not create a new MVC.
不会创建一个新的 MVC
It is the only segue that does not,
它唯一一种不会这样的
in the process of seguing, create a new instance of MVC.
在 segue 的过程中，创建一个新的 MVC
Okay?
好吗
It can only segue to an MVC that either directly or
他只能 segue 到一个 MVC 或者
indirectly presented the current MVC.
间接地展示当前的 MVC
So the MVC that wants to unwind to another MVC has to
所以 MVC 需要解开另一个已经被
have been presented directly or indirectly by that.
直接展示或者间接展示的 MVC
So what's it good for?
这样做有什么好处呢？
What does this unwind tell you,
解开的是什么东西
what do we ever use it for?
我们什么时候会用到呢？
Well, it's really good for
好了，这就是一个非常好的时刻
jumping back the stack of the navigation controller.
回到之前学习的 navigation controller 栈中
All right, so you got the navigation controller.
好的，你有一个 navigation controller
You've got six cards, you know, things stacked on there,
你有六张卡牌，你知道，有一叠在那
and you want to jump back to number two,
你需要返回到第二张
or all the way back to number one.
或者一直返回到第一张卡牌
Okay?
好吗
Well, in the navigation controller, each card down
在 navigation controller 中，每一张卡
is considered to have been presented by the previous one.
是被前一张卡片展示出来的
So it falls into this unwind segue thing where directly or
所以，unwind segue 能做的就是让你直接或者
indirectly you can go back up.
间接地回到之前的位置
Unwind up.
解开连接
So that's one good thing about it.
所以这是它的一个优点
Another one is you have an MVC that's modally presented.
另一个是，你有一个 MVC 并且是通过 modal 的方式展示的
Now again, I haven't talked really too much about modal
其实我还没有怎么说过 modal 类型的
presentation.
展示
I'm going to talk a little bit more about it today.
我今天就会讲到一点
But modal, I told you what modal is though.
但 modal，我告诉你 modal 是什么
Modal segue means take over the entire screen.
Modal segue 的意思就是取代整个屏幕
Even a pop over is basically modal, because when
pop over 就是一种 modal，因为
a popover's up you can't do anything except for
每当一个 popover 展示出来，除了这个 popover
what's in that popover.
其他的东西你都无法操作
The only other thing you can do is dismiss the popover by
你能够做的操作就是通过点击某处，来 dismiss
clicking somewhere else.
popover
So that's kind of modal.
这就是 modal
It puts your app in a mode where you can only work
他会让你的 app 进入某种模式，你只能操作
in that one space.
这个区域
So a lot of the time when a modal segue comes up
所以在大多数情况下，在使用了 model segue 视图显示在
on the screen, when it's done it wants to
屏幕上并且通过它我们得到了想要的
communicate some results back to whoever presented it, okay?
交互结果之后，就需要重新回到之前 present 的界面
So an unwind would be great for
所以 unwind 在这里使用再不过了
that because the only other alternative would be, like,
因为这里另一个关联就是
delegation.
委托
And, yes, you can have an MVC delegate back to another MVC,
是的，你也可以通过 MVC 委托回到另一个 MVC 中
because we remember that delegation is our view,
因为我们记得委托的是我们的视图
talking back blind to our controller.
回到之前绑定的控制器中
And remember that an MVC can be part of the view of another
但需要记住的是，一个 MVC 也可以是另一个 MVC 中的 View
MVC, so it's legal to use delegation.
所以使用委托也是可以的
But unwind, it's just a lot easier.
但 unwind，就会让事情变得更简单
Okay, unwind provides a little pipe for the modal segue to
unwind 会提供一些方法让 modal segue
unwind back to the one that presented it and
与之前 present 的控制器交流或者解绑
communicate with it, okay, by segueing to it, basically.
好吧，基本上是通过 segue 来做到这一点的
All right.
好了
So how does it work?
它是怎么使用的呢
Instead of Ctrl+dragging
之前的从另一个
from something to another MVC, okay?
MVC Ctrl+拖动 不同
You can't really Ctrl+drag to the presenter.
你不能在 presenter 那里 Ctrl+拖动
It might be in weird places in your storyboard.
这样在你的 storyboard 里面会很奇怪
It might not make sense.
完全没有道理
So instead, you Ctrl+drag to this little button at the top
以此代替，你可以在所有的 view controller 上 Ctrl+拖动这个
of every view controller which is called the Exit icon.
有 Exit 图标的小按钮
You see it there, it has the word exit.
你能够看到有个 Exit 在那
And when you Ctrl+drag to that exit, okay, to make the segue,
然后然你 Ctrl+拖动到那个按钮的时候，创建了 segue
it's gonna say, okay, where do you wanna segue to?
它会提示，你想要 segue 到哪里？
And instead of specifying a particular MVC,
与之前不同，不是指定特定的 MVC
you specify a special IBAction, okay?
你需要指定特定的一个 IBAction 控件
So my IBAction here I only wanna have is go back.
所以在我的 IBAction 这里我想要让他返回上一级
All right, that's the name of an IBAction method,
好了，这是 IBAction 方法的名字
somewhere in some MVC out there.
在某个 MVC 里面
Okay?
Now what's special about it is the argument of it,
特别之处在于参数
is a UI storyboard segue.
他是一个 UIStoryboard segue
The same argument that's given to prepare for segue, okay,
与 prepareForSegue 的参数相同
UI storyboard segue.
UIStoryboardSegue
That's what makes it special.
这就是其特别之处
So when you add an IBAction method to any MVC and
当你在任何一个 MVC 中添加了 IBAction 方法
the argument of it is a UI storyboard segue,
如果它的参数是 UIStoryboardSegue
then when people Ctrl+drag to their exit,
当大家 Ctrl+拖动到退出按钮的时候
they'll see it in this list, okay?
他们会看到这些方法出来列表中
So it can be any MVC anywhere.
所以他们可以在任何一个 MVC 中
Now of course if you try to unwind, and
当然如果你现在尝试着 unwind
you pick a method in an MVC, and
你选择了 MVC 中的一个方法
no MVC presented you that implements that method.
那么在 MVC 中你实现的这个方法
Then the unwind segue's gonna do nothing, okay?
unwind segue 不会有任何效果
Because it's not gonna be able to find a presenter who
因为它没有办法找到实现了
implements this method, okay?
这个方法的 presenter
So, but let's say you do have a presenter.
但这么说吧，你有一个 presenter
Let's say you're in a navigation controller and
假设你在一个 navigation controller 中
somebody who put you on screen has this method.
然后把你展示在屏幕上的某人有这个方法
Go back.
回去
You see it takes a UI story board segue there.
你看到一个 UIStoryboardSegue
Then if I wire up my unwind segue to that then I am
如果我连接了我的 unwind segue
basically going to be segueing back to that presenter.
那么我就可以 segue 回到那个 presenter
Okay, so that's how you hook it up, basically.
基本上这就是如何连接的
All right, now what happens once you get this hooked up?
好，那么当你连接这些东西之后会发生什么呢
So there has to be IBAction and
这里有个 IBAction
there has to be UIStoryboardSegue.
他们必须要有 UIStoryboardSegue 作为参数
Okay, otherwise IX code will not be able to detect
否则 Xcode 不能检测到
that possible unwind.
那些可以使用的 unwind
Okay, so when you segue, it is a normal segue
好了，当你 segue 的时候，这就是在 prepareForSegue： 中的
in that you get to prepare for segue, right?
一个普通的 segue 对吧
So the guy on the right there, he gets to implement
在右边的这个家伙，他实现了
prepareForSegue and when the unwind happens to his little
prepareForSegue 然后当 unwind 在他的退出按钮按下时
exit button, and he starts looking for
他就会开始寻找那个
that go back method somewhere in a presenter.
把他展示出来的类
He's going to get to prepare.
他就会得到 prepare
So you just implement normal prepareForSegue inside of
如果你就是实现了 prepareForSegue 的那个人
that guy, and the presenter, okay, is gonna get prepared.
作为展示者，就会需要准备好
And then the presenter's also going to have this go back
然后在 presenter 准备好了之后
method called after he's prepared.
他就会拥有这个方法
Okay?
So the presenter gets really prepared, kinda,
当一个 presenter 确实准备好了
or gets information twice.
他会得到两次这样的信息
It gets it once when it's preparedForSegue, because
第一次就是 preparedForSegue
it's the destination MVC and it's going to get prepared.
因为这就是 MVC 的目的，它就会准备好
Now it's already here so it's already pretty prepared but
现在它已经准备好了
maybe it gets prepared more.
但或许它需要再准备一下
And then when the Segue happens,
然后当 segue 发生了
go back will be called.
goBack 方法会被调用
And in the Segue that's passed as the argument there,
并且在这个 segue 参数这里
the presenter can find out who is segueing to me, and
presenter 可以知道是谁在向我 segue
what are they communicating to me?
到底是谁在向我联系
What do they want to communicate to me,
为什么他们要与我交流
in fact they can talk too, it uses public API to get
他们也确实可以交流，可以使用公共方法
whatever information they want.
获得他们想知道的任何信息
So basically it creates a link.
基本上会创建一个连接
So you will be dismissed in the process.
你可以在这个过程中 dismiss
When you unwind, when the user clicks on whatever you
当然你 unwind 当用户点击了任何你
control-dragged to that exit button, after this happens
之前 control-拖动到退出按钮的控件
you're gonna get always get dismissed.
那么你就会消失掉
Okay? So
那么
if you're in the navigation controller,
如果你在 navigation controller 里面
the navigation will pop back up to the presenter.
这个 navigation 将会返回到展示它的那个类那里
If you're modal, you will go away,
如果你是通过 modal 的方式展示你会消失
you'll stop taking over the whole screen.
不再接管整个屏幕
Okay?
So you are gonna unwind, that's why we kind of call it
如果你要 unwind，这也是为什么我们叫他
unwinding, you're wound up and now you kind of get unwound.
unwinding，你们会解开之间的联系
So yeah, so Modal segues,
好了，Modal segues
navigation controllers, exactly the same mechanism.
导航控制，基本上是相同的机制
All right, so that's it for unwind,
好了，这就是 unwind
it's as simple as that.
就是这么简单
You could possibly use unwind in your assignment
你可以根据你的需求
four if you want.
尽情地使用 unwind
I talk about it in the required task and the hints.
我会在附加任务中提到，并且有提示
It's not a required task,
这并不是一个必做的任务
it's just a way you could do it, okay?
这只是一个选项而已
And you can decide whether you wanna use an unwind or not.
你可以选择使用或者不使用 unwind
It would be a good experience for you to use an unwind.
如果你要使用 unwind 的话，这会是一个很好的例子
Question. >> Is the default background
学生提问
in the navigation controller actually doing that?
>> Yes. The question is,
>> 好的，问题是
is the back button unwinding?
是否回退按钮在处理 unwind
And the answer is no.
答案是不
That back button is wired to a method navigation controller,
回退按钮只是连接了 navigation controller 中的方法
called pop view controller.
叫做 pop view controller
And it just pops up,
它只是弹出了
so it doesn't get to do any of the unwinding.
所以并没有参与到 unwind 当中来
It doesn't get to be prepared, you don't get the,
它没有得到准备，而且你也不会
you don't have to implement that action with the,
你也不需要实现这个方法
so it's no, the answer is no [COUGH].
所以不，答案是不
Okay any other questions about unwind?
好了，有其他与 unwind 相关的问题吗？
Okay, next topic.
好了，下一个话题
Alerts and Action Sheets, okay?
Alerts 和 Action Sheets
So there are two kinds of "pop up and
在 iOS 中可以使用两种用来
ask the user something" mechanisms in iOS.
请求用户选择的弹出框
One is called an alert, and one is called an action sheet.
一种叫做 Alert，另一种叫 Action sheet
And they use, actually, exactly the same API.
而他们两的使用方法，基本上相同
You set them up in exactly the same way and
你通过同样的方式来设置他们
I'm gonna show you how that works.
我马上会向你演示如何操作
What's the difference between the two?
那么这两个东西之间有什么区别呢？
Okay. Alerts, first of all,
好，Alerts，但首先
they pop in the middle of the screen.
它们都会直接弹出出现在屏幕的中央
They're both modal.
他们都是 modal 的形式
Okay? They're both basically modal
他们基本上就是最基础的 modal
view controllers.
view controller
Okay? They're just kind of
他们只是有另一种显示的样式
drawn in a certain way, but they're really just a modal
但其实他们就是
view controller because they both take over the screen.
view controller，因为他们两都会掌管屏幕
But the alerts takes over the screen and
但 alerts 会接管屏幕并且
comes up right in the middle.
直接出现在中央
And usually alert is gonna ask you a question,
而且通常 Alert 会向你问一些问题
ask the user a question where there is only, kind of, one or
向用户询问那些只有一到两个
two answers.
答案的问题
Like yes no, or do this cancel, or
比如是或者否，或者要么取消
something like that.
要么做那个
An alert also, by the way, can also have a text field, so
同时，一个 alert 会有一个文本输入框
it could be like log in and
可以是登录
you have to type your password in there.
然后你可以在那输入你的密码
Okay or maybe even user name and password.
甚至用户名和密码
So it can collect text.
所以它可以可以收集文本
Action sheet cannot collect text from the user,
Action sheet 就不能从用户那收集文本
only the alert can do that.
只有 Alert 可以这样做
But if you had a question that had more than two answers to
但如果你有超过两个答案的问题
it you're probably going to use an action sheet.
那么你最好选择使用 Action sheet
Okay, so an action sheet.
好，Action sheet
It presents on screen a little differently.
它在屏幕上的样子稍微有点不同
It doesn't come up in the middle of the screen
它不会像 Alert 那样出现在
like an alert.
屏幕的正中间
It usually slides up from the bottom on an iPhone.
它同样从 iPhone 的底部滑出
On an IPad we usually put it up in a popover and
在 iPad 上我们通常会把它作为 popover 的形式出现
I'm going to show you how we do that in a moment.
我待会会向你展示是怎么做的
An action sheet is sometimes referred to as a branching
一个 Action Sheet 就是某种集结了一堆选项
decision sheet, so where you're basically making
的表单，也就是说你可以在用户需要在三到四个选项中
a branching decision where the user wants to
选择其中一件的时候
do one of three or four things and you're kind of picking
你可以通过它列出这一堆选项
which one you're going to do, and you're gonna head down
你可以把这个操作
that direction inside your app, okay?
内置在你的应用中
So I think by example
我想通过例子
is the easiest way to kind of see the difference here.
才是看出区别的最简单的方式
So, I took our Cassini out that we wrote, and I added a
在这里可以看到我们之前画的 Cassini 飞船，然后我在右上角
little button on the top that actually controls Cassini.
添加了一个小按钮来控制 Cassini
Okay, it'll redeploy Cassini off to different places, okay,
它可以重新部署 Cassini 飞到其他的地方
Saturn or can send it off to Titan or
土星或者泰坦
send it towards the sun, or whatever.
或者让它朝着太阳飞等等
Okay so I added that little redeploy button.
好了我添加的这个小小的重新部署按钮
You see it up in the right hand corner there?
你可以在右上角看到它吧
It says redeploy.
上面写着重新部署
So part of my implementation of allowing the scene to be
所以我的实现想法是通过 Action sheet 和 Alert
redeployed, I use an action sheet and an alert.
来重新部署场景
Okay?
So here's the action sheet I used.
这里是一个 Action sheet
When you click that redeploy button, it's gonna put up an
当你点击那个重新部署按钮，它会弹出一个
action sheet that says where do you wanna send Cassini to?
Action sheet 问你你想让 Cassini 去哪里？
I'm sure the Cassini guys have an app just like this,
我敢肯定控制 Cassini 的家伙肯定也有一个像这样的 App
it's how Cassini is controlled.
这一定就是 Cassini 被控制的方式
But, our app only lets them send it to Saturn, or
但，我们的应用只允许我们让它去土星或者
Titan, moon of, is that a moon of Jupiter, I guess?
泰坦，卫星，那是木星的卫星吗？我猜的
Or they can go take a closeup of the sun,
或者它可以到离太阳很近的地方
which is going to destroy Cassini.
这样做会摧毁掉 Cassini
Okay? Because it's too hot there.
因为那里太热了
Or they can cancel.
或者他们可以取消
So that's the action sheet that I invented.
这就是我创建的  Action sheet
And then if you decide you want to go somewhere,
如果你决定好了你想要去哪里
then I put up an alert that says oh, if you want to send
那么我就会弹出一个 Alert 问你，嘿，如果你想要让
Cassini to Titan, you need to login and give your guidance
Cassini 去泰坦，那么你需要登录并且交出
system control password or something, okay?
你的导航系统密码或随便什么
So this is my alert, okay?
所以这就是我的 Alert
So we're going to look at the code,
我们将要看一下代码
how I did this action sheet and alert.
我是怎么实现这个 Action sheet 和 Alert 的
Okay? So
let's start with the action sheet.
让我们从 Action sheet 开始
Now the code for both looks incredibly similar, so
这两个东西的代码看起来惊人地相似
what I'm teaching you here about action sheet,
所以我现在教你的 action sheeet
almost can be 100% applying to the alert.
几乎完全可以用在 alert 上
But basically in either case,
对于两种方案来说
you create an instance of a UIAlertController.
你都是在创建一个 UIAlertController 的实例
This is just a UI view controller, okay.
这就是一个 UIViewController
It's a sub class of a UI view controller [SOUND] that,
它是 UIViewController 的子类
you know, gets presented modally.
你懂的，
And that's basically it.
基本上就是这样
Okay, alerts and actions are basically a sub class of
Alerts 和 Actions 基本上就是 UIViewController
UI view controllers that get presented modally.
被以 modal 的形式展示了出来
They just happen to draw on these particular ways.
他们只是被某种特殊的实行画了出来
When you create your view control, you're going to give
当你创建 view controller 的时候，你需要给出一个
the title that you can see where the title Redeploy
标题，你可以在 action sheet 的最上面
Cassini appears there in my action sheet right at the top.
看到有个标题 "Redeploy Cassini"
And then the message,
然后是信息
which will appear right below it in non bold.
会在标题下面以非粗体的形式展示
That's actually probably using preferred fonts.
这是可能就是使用的 preferred fonts
So that's probably actually like a headline font and
这可能就是大标题粗体
a body font I'm guessing.
字号，我猜
And then you specify the preferred style.
但后你需要指定一个样式
So this is how you decide whether it's an action sheet
这里就是你决定显示为 action sheet
or an alert.
还是 alert
So here I'm doing action sheet so
那么我将选择 action sheet
I say UIAlertController style action sheet.
我填上 UIAlertController 样式 Action sheet
So that means I'm making an action sheet.
这就以为着我要制作一个 Action sheet
So that's it.
就是这样
I create my view controller.
我创建了我自己的 View Controller
Now I need to add some items into there like orbit Saturn,
现在我需要添加一些选项，比如土星轨道
explore Titan, close up of Sun, cancel.
勘探泰坦，靠近太阳，取消
How do I do that?
我要怎么做呢？
I do that by calling the method addAction on the alert
我通过 alert 来调用方法 addAction
on this view controller I just created.
在这个我刚刚创建的 view controller 上
And the argument to that is a UIAlertAction,
参数就是 UIAlertAction
which is another class that I'm going to create, which
这就是另一个我将要创建的类
really just kind of collects all of the information about
这基本上就是专门为了收集信息
a particular action.
的一个类
So here is how UIAlertAction looks like.
好了，这就是 UIAlertAction 的样子
It's got a title.
它需要一个标题
That's like Orbit Saturn there or Explore Titan,
比如土星轨道或这探索泰坦
that's the title.
这就是标题
It's got a style.
它需要样式
We'll talk about that in a second.
我们待会再来讲这个
And then it's got a handler, okay?
它还需要一个 handler
So here, you're starting to see closures again in
这里，你又会看到闭包出现在
the iOS API.
iOS API 中
This handler is just a closure, okay?
这个 handler 就是闭包
The argument is gonna be this action itself, so
这个参数就是这个 action 本身
it's basically like sender.
基本上就像 sender 一样
And inside this closure, you can do whatever you wanna do
在这个闭包里面，当点击这个 action 的时候
when they click on that particular action,
你可以做任何你想要做的事情
like Orbit Saturn.
比如土星轨道
So the code in there would probably go off and
在代码里面可能会是
send Cassini instructions to go Orbit Saturn, okay?
给 Cassini 发送命令，去土星轨道
So let's look at an example of one of these.
我们来看一个例子
Let's look at Orbit Saturn.
来看看土星轨道
The title is Orbit Saturn, the style is default, okay?
标题就是土星轨道，样式为默认
We'll talk about some other styles in a second here, but
等一下我们会讲到其他的样式
default is just the default line,
但现在就填默认样式
this blue colored text right there, like Orbit Saturn,
像土星轨道，探索泰坦这样，这种蓝色的文字，
Explore Titan, they're both that.
他们两就属于默认样式
And then the closure I'm
然后是闭包
gonna put is just to go into orbit around Saturn.
我将会直接进入土星环形轨道
And similarly, Explore Titan would look exactly the same,
同样的，探索泰坦也使用
also default style.
完全相同的默认样式
And maybe Cassini's mission was I think to orbit Saturn or
我想的 Cassini 的任务是
go to Saturn.
去土星
So maybe if you're gonna switch it over to going to
或许你可以修改为去
Titan then you have to log in and do your guidance password.
泰坦，然后你需要登录并且输入你的导航密码
Otherwise, you can always send Cassini back to
除此之外，你也可以让 Cassini 回去或者去
Saturn, I guess.
土星，我猜
Okay.
好了
So there's the example of the default actions.
这就是默认 actions 的例子
So let's look at the next one, that Closeup of Sun.
让我们来看看下一个，靠近太阳
So the Closeup of Sun is almost exactly the same except
靠近太阳也几乎与刚才一样
for its style is not default, it's .Destructive.
除了它的样式不是默认，而是 .Destructive
Okay?
好吗
So .Destructive makes it show up in red.
.Destructive 会让文字变成红色
So anything that's gonna really damage something,
所以任何会造成损害的事情
like delete this entry, or something like that,
比如删除这个实例，或者其他的东西
you can make it .Destructive and it will show up in red.
你就可以使用 .Destructive 然后它就会显示为红色
Okay.
Otherwise, it's exactly the same as the other ones.
除此之外还有另一个样式
And then the Cancel one also has a special thing, .Cancel.
对于取消来说，也有一个特殊的东西 .Cancel
All right?
好吧
And you can see that Cancel is
你可以看到取消
kinda separated from the rest of em?
是与其他选项分开的
It's down at the bottom, it's got a little extra space.
它在最下面，并且有额外的一点空间
That's pretty much the only difference between Cancel,
这基本上就是取消样式的唯一区别了
cuz you still get a closure there you get to execute,
因为你仍然可以在点击它的时候
when it's clicked on.
执行一个闭包
Okay, so that's it.
好了，就是这样
So, alerts couldn't be any simpler to create, okay?
Alerts 已经不能更简单了
So that's how you create this view controller and
这就是你怎么创建这个 view controller 并且
configure it with its actions.
配置它的行为
Now, how do we put this thing on screen?
现在，我们应该怎么把它放在屏幕上呢
How do we get this alert to actually slide up
我们怎么才能让这个 alert 从
from the bottom?
底部滑上去呢
Well, it's just a UIViewController,
它其实就是 UIViewController
we're gonna present it modally.
我们只要通过 modal 的方式来 present
So, there's a method in UIViewController called
好，在 UIViewController 中有一个方法叫做
presentViewController.
presentViewConroller
I haven't really talked about it cause
我还没有怎么说过它
we haven't talked about modal presentation.
因为我们还没有谈过 model 的展示方式
But all presentViewController is,
但 presentViewController 的作用就是这个
it presents a view controller on screen.
让一个 view controller 展示在屏幕上
And if it's a modal view controller like alerts are,
而且如果它是一个 modal view controller 比如 alert
it'll appear modally.
它就会 modal 的方式出现
Okay? It only has three arguments
懂了吗，它只有三个参数
which is the UIViewController to present,
展示哪个 UIViewController
whether to animate it so in the case of the action sheet,
是否执行动画，我们这里是 action sheet
it slides up from the bottom.
所以它会从底部划上去
And then you also get a closure there,
然后你会得到一个闭包
completion, which will get called, this is closure,
completion，它会被调用，这是个闭包
it takes no arguments, returns nothing.
没有参数，也不需要返回任何东西
It'll have when it's done.
执行完成就完了
So when that thing has been finally presented on screen
当某个东西最终被展示到了屏幕上
and done its animation, boom,
完成了它的动画， BOOM
you'll get your completion called.
你的 completion 会被调用
You almost never do anything there.
你几乎不会在这里做任何事
It's really, doesn't make a lot of sense.
这也确实没有什么道理
The things already up, it's doing its business.
东西已经被展示出来了，那么就已经完成了工作
There's really no business for you, as its presenter,
作为它的展示者，在这个时刻
to be doing at that point, but you could, okay?
这里已经没有事情需要你来做了，但你有这个选项
So that's it, UIAlerts are just UIViewController.
好了，就是这样， UIAlerts 就是 UIViewController
Just add actions to them, then you present them.
只是添加一些动作，然后你展示他们
Now, what about this action sheet thing though on an iPad?
现在要说的是，这个 Action sheet 在 iPad 上是怎么作用的呢？
Okay? So here's same app in iPad and
在 iPad 上有这么一个相同的应用
I got that redeploy button up there in the right.
右上角仍然有一个重新部署按钮
Now look what happens when I do redeploy in the iPad.
来看看当我在 iPad 上按下重新部署
Same thing.
同样的
But it shows up in a popover.
但它展示为弹出框
Okay? It doesn't
它没有
slide up from the bottom.
从底部滑上来
It wouldn't look very good if it slid up from the bottom.
从底部滑上来也不会很好看
It would either be kinda silly narrow, or
这样会有点狭窄样子
it would be so fat and wide it would look ridiculous.
或者会看起来很宽很胖，看起来很荒谬
It makes much more sense to put it in a popover like that.
作为弹出框的形式来出来要合理得多
Notice that the popover is different in one big way.
从另一个方面来说弹出框也是不同的
No cancel button, okay?
没有取消按钮
And that's because you don't need a cancel button to
你也不需要一个取消按钮
cancel a popover.
来取消弹出框
A popover is modal, and if you click anywhere else in your
一个弹出框是 modal 的形式，如果你在应用的任何一个地方点击了
app, boom, it's gonna cancel that popover.
BOOM，它就会取消这个弹出框
But if you have a cancel action, like this one does,
但如果你有一个取消的 action，就像这个一样
its actions still will be called,
那么 action 仍然会被调用
even in the popover cancel case.
即使是弹出框取消这样的情况
Okay?
So that cancel thing is kind of still in play,
所以取消操作仍然会存在
it's just that you access it differently.
只是另一种方式
Instead of hitting the Cancel button like the bottom of
不是像 iPhone 应用那样点击底部的取消按钮
the iPhone version, you just click somewhere else and
而是点击其他的地方
make the popover go away.
来让弹出框消失
Everyone understand that?
大家明白了吗？
All right, but how do we make this work?
好了，但现在我们要怎么让这个运行呢？
Because this is not quite enough information
因为目前来看没有足够的信息
to present that popover, okay?
来展示这个弹出框，对吧
That popover needs one really important piece of
这个弹出框需要一个非常重要的信息
information, which is who is popping me up?
那就是，谁让我弹出的？
Because you see it has that little white triangle
因为你看这里顶部有一个白色的小三角形
at the top that's pointing to redeploy?
指着重新部署按钮对吧
So nowhere here are we saying, oh, Mr.
那就是我们在某个地方说，弹出框先生
Popover, point to that redeploy button, okay?
指着那个重新部署按钮吧
So we need to say that.
所以我们需要这样说
So that means when we put any action sheet up and it's
这也意味着当我们把一个弹出框
gonna happen on an iPad where there might be a popover.
放在 iPad 上时，我们需要告诉它在哪里弹出
We need to get a hold of the popover
我们需要获取到这个悬浮
presentation controller.
展示的 controller
The same one we got ahold of, back when we were doing
与在之前那个应用中同样的获取方式
the popover in the previous app, the psychologist app.
那个心理学应用
Same popover presentation controller.
同样的弹出弹出框
We need to get it and we just need to tell it,
我们需要获取它，并且我们要告诉它
here's the button that's presenting you, so
这里有个按钮，就是它要弹出你
you can point to it.
所以你可以指着它
Okay?
对吧
So we do that like this.
我们就这么做
First of all,
首先
just have to say that the alerts presentation style,
告诉 alert 的展示样式
its modal presentation style, is popover presentation style.
是 modal 展示样式，这就是弹出框展示样式
If we don't tell it that, then it will never make a popover
如果我们不告诉它，那么它也永远不会成为一个
presentation controller.
悬浮展示控制器
So we can't tell it anything cause it won't exist.
由于其不存在那么我们就什么都不能做
But once we say that this UIViewController
一旦我们说，这是一个 UIViewController
modalPresentationStyle is a popover, now we can say okay,
modalPresentationStyle 就是弹出框，那么就可以了
well give me the popover presentation controller.
它就会给我们一个悬浮展示 controller
And the BarButtonItem,
还有 BarButtonItem
which is that redeploy up there is this.
这就是重新部署按钮
And so I point it to the redeployBarButtonItem, and
所以我填写 redeployBarButtonItem
now when it pops over, when it gets presented modally here,
当它被以 modal 的方式展示时，就会从那里弹出
using a popover presentation,
使用 popover presentation
it will point to the redeployButton, okay?
它会指着重新部署按钮
The cool thing is because of adaptive UIs,
这也是非常酷的一个东西，因为它的 UI 是自适应的
which we talked about back then,
我们之前谈到过
is that this code works exactly the same on iPhone.
这段代码同样可以在 iPhone 上使用
So if you put in those three lines to make the popover
你添加的这三行让弹出框运行的代码
work, it won't effect the iPhone at all.
完全不会影响到 iPhone
Because the iPhone already adapts popovers to present
因为 iPhone 已经自适应了弹出框
over the whole screen, remember?
为整个屏幕，记得吗
And in fact, we had to go do some work in psychologists
事实上我们在心理学应用中做了一些额外的工作
to stop it from doing that adapting.
来让它不要自适应
So that it would show up in a little popover on the phone.
所以这样会展示一个弹出框在手机上
But if you don't do any of that work,
但如果你什么也不做
then by default it shows just like this.
默认它就会这样显示
Until it takes over the whole screen on the iPhone.
直到它掌控整个 iPhone 屏幕
So that's why setting the modal presentation style to
所以，自适应，这就是为什么我们设置了 modal presentation 样式
popover still works on the iPhone because it adapts.
但在 iPhone 上仍然起效的原因
Okay?
Any questions about that?
有任何问题吗？
So that's how you do an action sheet.
这就是你使用 Action Sheet 的方式
You're gonna do the same body of code you see right there
在你所有的 Action sheet 中你都需要使用
for every action sheet you ever do.
这些同样的代码
All right, now, let's go talk about the alert.
好了， 现在让我们来谈谈 Alert
Okay.
The only difference in creating the view controller
唯一的不同就是，当你在创建 view controller 的时候
is you say that its style is alert instead of action sheet.
你需要设置它的样式为 alert 而不是 action sheet
Otherwise, it's exactly the same.
除此之外，其他的都一模一样
Okay, iPad different text here,
好了，iPad 有一点不同的文本
obviously login required and please enter your Cassini
很明显当你在进入  Cassini 的导航系统时
guidance system password instead of the other things.
你需要登录输入密码
But, otherwise I'm just changing
但除此之外就只需要修改
the style to be alert.
样式为 alert
I do the same thing with adding actions.
添加 action 也是同样的方式
So, here I'm gonna add the Cancel button.
这里我们要添加一个取消按钮
Okay, I'm gonna add the Login button.
好的，我还要添加一个登录按钮
Now the interesting thing about the Login button is when
有趣的部分来了，当我点击这个登录按钮的时候
I login I wanna get the text out of that text field
我想要一个文本输入框弹出来
to use as a password for my guidance system, okay?
问我要登录导航系统的密码
So how am I gonna do that, okay.
这就是我要做的
Well first of all we're gonna ask,
首先我们需要问的是
how do I put that text field there?
我怎么才能在这里放一个文本输入框？
Okay, I've gotta put that text field in my alert.
好了已经放了一个文本输入框在我的 Alert 里
So here's how we put a text field in alert.
这就是我们如何把输入框放在 Alert 中
Use simple method addTextFieldWithConfiguration-
使用了一个很简单的方法 addTextFieldWithConfigurationHandler
Handler, okay?
对吧
When you call that, it adds the text field to the alert
当你调用它时，它就会给 Alert 添加一个输入框
and it calls this closure so
然后它会调用这个闭包函数
that you can configure the text field however you want.
这样你才能配置这个输入框为你想要的样式
So here my text field,
这就是我的输入框
I configured it to say Guidance System Password
我配置它显示"导航系统密码"
as the place holder text there in the background.
在这里作为文字占位符
Remember in the smash tag,
记得这个标签
I had my search field say Twitter Search Query.
之前有一个搜索输入框显示搜索 Twitter
Well, here I'm having
在之类我们需要显示
this one say Guidance System Password in the background.
导航系统密码
And that's it.
就是这样
So I could do other things to set the font or
我也可以做一些其他的事，比如设置字体
whatever I want of the text field there.
或者其他我可以对输入框做的事
And you can call
你可以调用
addTextFieldWithConfiguration- Handler more than once and
addTextFieldWithConfiguration 多次来添加
then you'll get more than one text field.
不止一个输入框
So you could have a login and a password field.
这样你就可以有登录和密码输入框
Now.
This is great, I've got the text field in there.
很棒，我们有一个输入框了
When I click log in inside the action for
当我在 action 中点击了 login
log in, how do I get the text out of that text field, okay?
我应该怎么获取这些文字呢
Well, that looks slightly more complicated than you might
这会看起来比你想像的稍微复杂一点
like, it looks like this.
看起来像这样
I'm going to let TF, which is going to be a pointer to that
我需要使用 let tf，这会指向刚才那个
text field equal alert.text fields.
输入框，= alert.textfields
Which is an array of any object
这会是一个可能为任何元素在里面的
in its optional array, okay?
optionanl 数组
So, since it's an array, since it's optional,
由于它是一个数组，由于它是可选的
I'm gonna put a question mark there so
我需要在这里加上一个 ?
that I can do this optional chaining and just fail.
这样我才能使用这个 optional chaininng，而且可能失败
So TF, let TF, that could be nil,
因为 let tf 可能为 nil
that could end up being nil.
这个可能为 nil
That's a question mark, and then I'm gonna say .first.
这是一个 ? 然后我要加上 .first
If you remember an array,
如果你记得 array 中的这个方法
the method .first returns the first thing in the array
.first 返回数组中第一个元素
if the array has anything in it.
如果数组中有东西的话
If not, it returns nil.
如果没有返回 nil
So that's a great way to get something,
这就是一个很好的办法来获取元素
the first thing out of an array and
在不检查数组中是否有东西的情况下
not have to check to see if anything's in the array.
获取数组中的第一个元素
And it'll just return nil if there's nothing in the array.
如果没有东西的话，就会返回 nil
And then I've got to cast it to a text field because I told
然后我需要转换为 text field 因为
you it was an array of any object.
我之前说过这是一个 anyObject 泛型的数组
Why is it an array of any object?
为什么泛型为 anyObject？
Don't ask, historical reasons.
别在意，历史原因
It's a way objective C cat does things,
这是之前 Objective-C 中遗留的东西
it's not quite as expressive as Swift.
它没有 Swift 这样丰富的表现力
But, anyway, too bad.
但，也不糟糕
So you do this as ?,
所以你使用的这个 as ?
so that also could return nil.
它仍然可能返回 nil
So, it's three different things that could return nil,
所以这里有三个东西可能返回 nil
but if they don't, then I'm gonna get text field back.
但如果它们没有，我就会得到输入框
And if I get a text field back,
当我获取到这个输入框的时候
then I can just take the text out of the text field and
我就可以把文本从输入框中取出
log in.
然后登录
Okay?
Any questions about that?
有人有问题吗？
I know it's a little convoluted getting
我知道取出输入框
that text field out of there.
这里有点绕
All right?
So that's it for alerts.
好，这就是 Alert
Then you just present view controller exactly the same
然后你需要像之前那样 presentViewController
as we did for action sheet or any other modal view.
就像我们对 Action sheet 和其他的 modal view 做得那样
And how about an iPad?
那 iPad 上呢？
An iPad?
一个 iPad？
It looks exactly the same.
它看起来一模一样
Takes over the whole screen.
接管整个屏幕
No need to do any popover business with alerts on iPad.
在 iPad 上 Alert 不需要做额外的操作
Okay.
So that's alerts and action sheets.
这就是 Alerts 和 Action sheets
Just UIV controls that you're presenting modally
就是你 modal 地展示一个 UIViewController
that's all they are.
这就是全部了
All right.
好了
Next topic, NSTimer.
下一个话题，NSTimer
So NSTimer is a way to set up a timer
NSTimer 是一种设置定时器的东西
that will call a method periodically, okay?
可以周期性地调用一个方法
Now, it uses technology called RunLoop,
它使用的技术叫做 RunLoop
which we're not going to talk about.
我们不会讲这个东西
So suffice it to say, for you, in this course,
在这个课堂中，对于你们来说只要知道
you always have to use timers on the main queue, okay?
永远在主队列中使用定时器就行了
Because the main queue has a run loop.
因为主队列有 run loop
You can actually have run loops on other queues,
你其实可以在其他队列使用 run loop
other threads, but we're not gonna talk about that.
在其他线程，但我们不会讲这个东西
So, main queue for you, NSTimer main queue.
所以主队列，NSTimer 主队列
And, so this timer, it's not really a real-time timer.
而且，这个定时器，其实并不是实时的计时器
If you say go off every two seconds,
你写每两秒启动一次
it's not going to go off every 2.00000 seconds.
它其实并不会每2.00000秒执行一次
And why is that?
这是为什么呢？
Because basically it's just putting things,
因为它只是放置事件
it's kind of like it's putting things on the main queue but
就像它放置一些事件在主队列中，
not, not quite the same.
不，也不完全一样
The runloop helps process things that are happening,
runloop 会帮助执行让事件发生
like interrupts or data that becomes available or whatever.
就像打断或者数据有效或者其他
And it can't run in real-time,
但它不能实时执行
because other things are on the main queue running.
因为其他的事件也在主队列中执行
Okay? Other
其他的代码
blocks of code and stuff.
或者什么东西
So we can't quite guarantee it.
所以我们不能保证
But it has a high priority, so,
但它确实有很高的优先级，所以
as soon as the main queue becomes available, after
只要主队列空闲下来了
2.0000 seconds has happened, it's gonna call your method.
在2.000000秒之后，它就会调用你的方法
Okay, but it's not a real time programming thing.
但这确实不是实时编码的
I mentioned that for those of you who are like systems
我提起这个是为了那些喜欢研究系统的并且
OS people and you're used to real time API.
熟悉实时 API 的人
This is not real time but it's really, really,
这不是实时的，但它确实非常非常
really close to real time.
非常接近实时
As long as you don't have any big things on your main queue
不要在你的主队列中处理一些笨重的
that are blocking it up which you shouldn't have any
会阻塞线程的事件，这样就没有
way, right?
什么办法了
Never block your main queue.
永远不要阻塞你的主线程
Then your timer's pretty much gonna run when you want.
那么你的定时器基本上就会按照你期待的方式运行
Okay?
Now this is not used for animation.
这也并不是用来制作动画的
We're going to talk all about animation later today and
我们待会以及下周一整周
all of next week.
都会讲动画
And your assignment five is
而且你的第五个任务也完全是
going to be all about animation.
与动画相关的
Timer is more like a complement to animation.
但定时器对于动画来说更像一个补充的东西
Because when you're animating things sometimes you do want
当你在执行动画的时候，你想要
to do things.
做一些其他的事情
Something every second or every two seconds.
一些每秒或每两秒执行的事
You're really not going to be, like,
但你不会
doing something every 60th of a second.
每六十分之一秒做一次
Okay? 60 frames per
六十帧每秒
second animation,
的动画
you'd never do that with a timer, it's not for that.
你永远也不要通过定时器来做这个，它并不是用来做这个的
Okay?
好吗
It's just for things like, maybe,
它只是用来，比如
you have something where you have a score in a game and
你在游戏中有一个什么比分
you update the score every second.
你需要每秒更新一次
Okay?
So that you're not constantly changing it,
这样不需要自己频繁地去改变
something like that.
类似这样
It's that kind of thing.
这种事
It's used for that kinda thing.
它是用来做这种事的
So run loops we're not going to talk about that.
所以我们不会讲到 run loop
Okay so how do you fire off one of these timers?
你怎么知道如何启动其中一个定时器呢
How do you make it work?
你怎么才能让它生效？
Well you do it with a class function in NSTimer.
你只需要调用 NSTimer 的一个类方法
It's called a scheduled timer with time interval.
叫做 scheduledTimerWithTimeInterval
Now be careful.
注意
There are four methods in NSTime but it looked very,
在 NSTimer 中有四个方法，但它们长得
very similar to this.
和这个很像
Okay? But
但
this is the one you want with this set of arguments [SOUND].
这才是你需要的
And the arguments are just,
它的参数就是
the first one is how many seconds between firings?
第一个就是启动的间隔时间
How many seconds do you want to wait each time before you
你希望它在调用了一次方法之后，等待多少秒
call this method again?
再调用这个方法
The target is, who you gonna send the message to?
target 是，你希望向谁发送消息
It can be any object.
它可以是任何对象
Okay?
Remember, any object is not a struct or an enum.
记住，任何对象不是指 struct 或者 enum
Although, things like string and number, those are.
虽然像 string 和 number 这种他们是
You're not gonna solve puzzles anyway but
但你不能这样做
those are essentially any object because they're
它们本质上是 anyObject 这是由于它们与 NSString
bridging over to NS String.
有桥接
But anyway, any object, okay, is any object,
除此之外，任何对象，anyObject
any class basically, and then selector is just
基本上任何类，然后 selector 是
the method to call when the timer goes off.
你需要定时器执行的方法
User info is just like a cookie that you can
userInfo 就类似于 cookie，你可以
hand off here and then every time it fires you'll be giving
在这里存入，然后每次调用的时候，你都可以
that thing back.
把它取回来
So, it's just kind of a way of passing this argument off
这样就可以传递参数
to your, so you don't have to keep it in a class,
你不需要把它保存在类中
in a variable in your class or anything like that.
以变量的形式存在你的类中，或者其他的方法
You can just hand it off.
你可以只是存进去
It's like context for the timer.
就像定时器的上下文
And then repeat is whether this thing just does it once,
然后 repeat 就是这个定时器是否只执行一次
or it keeps doing it every however many seconds.
还是每隔几秒执行一次
Is it a repeating timer, or is it just a one time
它是重复执行的定时器还是只在未来执行
do something in the future, and I showed you a way to do
一次任务，上次我用 dispatch 向你展示了一种
one time thing in the future with dispatch last time, so
在未来只执行一次任务的的方法
this will be another way to do something once.
这是另一个在未来执行的方法
Here's an example of calling it.
这里有一个使用的例子
So here I have a timer.
我有一个定时器
It's gonna go off every two seconds.
它会每隔两秒调用一次
It's gonna send this message to myself called fire.
它会每隔两秒向自身发送一次消息
Notice that, that method can be any name you want,
注意，这个方法可以是任何你想要的方法
except it has to have a colon there,
除了，你必须在这里加上一个冒号
because it's going to have an argument.
因为它需要一个参数
I told you that when you're specifying the name of
之前我有提到过，当你需要指定一个方法的时候
a method, if it has an argument,
如果它有参数
you have to put a colon on the end.
那么你就必须添加一个冒号在最后
OK. Otherwise it
否则
thinks it's the method fire without an argument.
它会去执行没有参数的方法
And then userInfo on passing nil.
那么 userInfo 就不会被传递
I don't really want any information,
我确实不需要什么信息
I could pass anything, any object I wanted there.
我可以传入任何我想要的参数，任何对象
And then repeats equals true means it's going to fire
repeats = true 意思是它会每隔
every two seconds.
两秒执行一次
It's going to fire in two seconds from now, and
它会从现在开始两秒执行一次
two seconds after that, and two seconds after that.
两秒后再执行一次，过两秒再执行
Repeat it forever until I invalidate it, okay?
一直不断重复直到我销毁了它
So let's look now at the fire timer thing.
让我们来看看执行定时器的东西
It looks like this.
它看起来像这样
You can basically do whatever you want in there.
你可以在里面做任何事情
You're on the main queue so
你在主队列，所以
you can do UI in here or whatever.
你可以设置 UI 或者其他的事
If you pass some user info, you can get it
如果你传入了 userInfo，那么你可以通过
out of the timer by saying the timer.userinfo.
定时器得到，使用 timer.userInfo
Now you've got that info.
现在你就获得了那个信息
Okay?
Super simple to use these timers.
使用定时器非常简单
If you wanna stop a timer that's repeating,
如果你想要让定时器停止重复
it's going off every two seconds and you wanna stop it,
它会每隔两秒执行一次，而你想要停止
you just send it the message, invalidate.
你只需要向它发送一个消息，销毁
If you say timer.invalidate, it will stop.
如果你调用 timer.invalidate 它就会停止
Okay?
Another thing you can do to make your system perform
你还可以通过使用 tolerance 来让系统性能
better is put a tolerance in there.
更好一些
What a tolerance says, is if my two, if I'm
tolerance 的作用是，比如我
setting something to go off every two minutes let's say.
设置了一个定时器它会每两分钟执行一次
Okay?
When the two minutes is up do I have to do it right away?
当两分钟到了它会立刻执行对吧？
Or can I wait five or ten seconds?
或者我可以等待五或者十秒
If you let the system wait five or
如果你让系统等待五或者十秒
ten seconds, it could pick an optimal time to call your,
它会选择一个时间来调用你
a more optimal time, anyway, to call your timer.
在一个更合适的时间，来执行你的定时器
So, my strong recommendation is, try to give a tolerance.
所以我的建议是使用 tolerance
A tolerance is just a number of seconds that you're
tolerance 只是设置一个以秒为单位的时间
willing to wait after it would normally fire.
在执行事件之前的等待
Try to give a tolerance of like maybe 10% of your timer.
尝试给 tolerance 比如定时器十分之一的时间
So if you have a two second timer,
比如你有一个2秒的定时器
give it a tolerance of 0.2 seconds or
给它的 tolerance 0.2 秒或者
something like that.
类似的值
It'll let the system pick a more efficient time to run.
这样会让系统选择一个更为高效的时间来执行
Like, for example, if your app, we didn't
举个例子，如果你的应用
really explain how this works, but your device can kind of
我们没有解释到底这个是怎么工作的
go to sleep a little bit when nothing's happening.
但如果你的应用可以在没有事情的时候闲置一下
Nothing's drawing on screen, no network activity.
没有在屏幕上画图，没有发送网络请求
So it can kind of go into a little lower power state, and
这样系统就可以进入一个短暂的低功耗状态
then it comes back awake every once in awhile.
然后它每隔一会就会恢复
Well, if you give it a little tolerant,
所以如果你设置了一会 tolerant
it might be able to kind of go into that low power state and
系统就可以进入低功耗状态
then come back up in that little window.
然后再回来
But if you don't give it a tolerance,
如果你不设置 tolerance
it might have to stay awake to make sure it hits that timer,
那么它就会一直保持唤醒的状态，以确保定时器的触发
the one you wanted.
就像你想的那样
You see?
你明白了吗？
So the tolerance is exactly what it sounds like.
所以 tolerance 就是听上去的那个意思，容忍误差
A little bit of tolerance, give the system a little
一点点误差可以让系统更好地
better chance to manage your battery and all that.
管理你的系统及其他
Okay?
If you give it tolerance, it's not going to drift.
如果设置了 tolerance，它也并不会滞后
In other words, if you give a tolerance 2 minute timer and
换句话说，如果你设置了两分钟的定时器
you let it go an extra 10 seconds and
然后你让它执行了十秒
it waits an extra 8 seconds, the next one is not going to
然后等待八秒，下一次定时器触发并不会
be 2 minutes after that 2 minutes and 8 seconds.
是在两分钟加两分钟加八分钟之后
It's still going to be 2 minutes after the first
它仍然会在第一次执行之后的的两分钟
2 minutes.
再次触发
Do you see what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思了吗
Within the tolerance.
在容忍误差的情况下
So it's going to stay on a schedule of every two minutes,
它仍然会保持两分钟的计划
even if it waits a little bit on one or two or three.
即使它会等待一两秒
It doesn't drift.
但它不会延后
Okay, that's timer.
好了，这就是定时器
Okay. Any questions about that?
有人有相关的问题吗？
It's a pretty cool little guy.
这是个非常有趣的东西
All right.
好了
Animation.
动画
So, this is kind of Intro to Animation,
这堂课最后的十分钟将
this last ten minutes of today's lecture.
只是介绍一下动画
So, let me talk a little bit about the kinds of animation
让我们来聊一下到底有哪几种动画
that you can do in iOS.
你可以在 iOS 中使用
One is to animate the properties of a view.
一个是使 view 的属性执行动画
And that's what we're going to talk about today.
这也是我们今天将会谈到的
So that's one kind of animation.
这是一种动画
Another one is animation of view controller transitions,
另一种是 view controller 转场
like in a navigation controller,
比如在 navigation controller
when you transition to the next card on the stack or
当你从栈中转场到另一张卡
something like that.
类似于这样
Or even a modal view controller like the UI alert,
或者说 modal view controller 比如 UIAlert
or the action sheet that slides up from the bottom.
或 Action sheet 从底部滑出
Okay, that's another kind of animation, obviously.
明显这又是另一种动画
Okay we're not going to talk about view controller
我们不会在这节课中讲到 view controller
transition animation in this class.
转场动画
It's not really that terribly difficult, but
这也不是很难，只是
it's just like I got to pick things to talk about and
我总要选择一些东西来讲，但这个东西没有
that one, we're not going to talk about, okay?
被选中，所以我们不会讲这个东西
But there is infrastructure for doing that.
这有基础设置用来完成
There's also something called Core Animation.
还有另一种动画叫做 Core Animation
Okay, Core Animation is this incredibly powerful animation
Core Animation 是在 UIView Core Animation 动画
engine that underlies
底层的一种
all of this UIView animation that's going on.
非常强大的动画引擎
And Core Animation can animate arbitrary properties
而且 Core Animation 可以操纵大量属性执行动画
over time.
And it knows how to juggle them and
而且它知道应该在何时
knows how to present them on screen over time.
展示在屏幕上
It's really super powerful.
它真的非常强大
Unfortunately, I can't talk about that either.
但不幸的是，同样我也不会讲这个
Okay. Don't have time for that.
没有这么多时间
But if you're going to do something serious animation
但如果你想要在视图中创造一些真正的动画
inside views and you're not going to use the next kind I'm
那么你不会想要使用我接下来将要将的
going to talk about, Core Animation, know that it's
动画。Core Animation
there because you will eventually have to learn it.
这个东西你最终还是要学的
Okay.
And the last one's called dynamic animation.
好了，最后一种动画叫做力学动画
That's physics-based animation.
这是基于物理引擎的动画
So that's giving views gravity and collision boundaries and
它会赋予视图重力和碰撞
other behaviors like friction and density, and
还有其他的行为比如摩擦力和密度
then saying, go.
然后执行
Okay? And
then they'll just behave, okay.
它们就会运转
So that's dynamic behavior based animation, and
所以这就是力学表现动画
that's what we're going to talk about on Wednesday.
我们将会在周三的时候讲到
And that's what your assignment five is
这也是你任务五
mostly going to be about.
大部分要使用的东西
Assignment five's going to do a little bit of
任务五会有一些视图动画，我会在
view animation, which I'm going to talk about today, and
这周讲一些
then a lot of dynamic animation.
然后很多的力学动画
Okay?
And why do we have dynamic animation?
什么我们需要力学动画？
Why do we have this physics thing?
为什么我们需要这个物理的东西
If you ever watch an iPhone app, you know,
如果你曾经使用过 iPhone 应用
if you flip things up and let them drop down.
如果你拨动了某个东西然后让它们坠落
Don't do it now, but if you get your iPhones out and
不要现在做啦，但你如果你已经把 iPhone 拿出来了
you go to the very front, even if it's locked, and
你在解锁界面，即使它是锁住的
you pull down your notifications, you'll notice
然后你下拉你的通知窗口，你可以发现
they will kind of hit the bottom and bounce a little.
它们会撞击底部然后弹起来一点
Okay?
对吧
It won't just kind of pull it down and
它不会只是下拉
it won't just go clunk, it goes boom.
不会只是哐当到底部
Okay? It kind of gives
它展示一个
a soft landing.
柔软地着落
And that kind of animation turns out to
这种动画效果
be surprisingly important for the user experience.
对于用户体验来说非常重要
It makes the user feel a little more like oh, yeah,
这会让用户感觉，就像
it's kind of giving a constant warm fuzzy feeling about
它会给你一种非常温暖毛茸茸的感觉
what's going on, as opposed to feeling like a computer that
而不是感觉就像机器
is slamming things around, okay.
在直接碰地执行
So, dynamic animation is really important for
所以力学动画是非常重要的
giving that really kind of homey feel to your UI.
可以让你的 UI 有一种熟悉的感觉
Warm feel, okay?
温暖的感觉
So that's why we spend a lecture on it next time.
这就是为什么我们下一节课会讲这个
All right, so let's talk about animating view properties.
让了让我们来讲讲视图属性的动画
Only certain properties can be animated at the UIView level.
视图只有部分属性可以用来执行动画
If you go down to Core Animation, you can do more,
如果你用 Core Animation，那么可以使用更多
but at UIView level,
但在 UIView 这个层次
you can really, the three that are most important to animate
你只能操作三种最主要的动画
are the frame, that means moving your view around.
frame，这意味这你可以让你的视图到处移动
The transform, that means rotating your view or
transform，这意味着你可以旋转你的视图
scaling it in and out.
或者让它变大变小
And the opacity, the alpha.
然后是透明度，alpha
Okay.
So you can use this kind of animation to
你可以使用这种动画
fade things out using the alpha or to move around,
来让东西淡出或者让它到处移动
although they won't move with this nice physics base.
虽然它们并不会移动那么真实
So I kind of recommend the dynamic animation for
所以我推荐使用力学动画来操作
moving things.
移动
But it's really nice for alpha for fading things around, or
但这个用来执行渐隐渐现的动画还是很不错的
if you're going to have rotating views,
以及如果你需要旋转视图
views that rotate.
视图被旋转
So how do we do this animation with these properties?
那么我们应该怎么操作属性呢？
It's done with class methods on UIView and closures, okay?
它使用 UIView 带有闭包函数的方法
So you have this class method.
你可以看到这个类方法
You basically say what kind of animation you want,
你基本上就是调用你想要的动画
how long you want it to take, things like that.
你想要它执行多久，类似于这样
And then you just provide a closure, and
然后你可以得到一个闭包
inside that closure you change these properties, frame,
在这个闭包中你可以修改这些属性，frame
transform, alpha.
transform，alpha
Just change them.
修改它们
Okay?
And then the system
然后系统会
will animate those changes over time.
在指定时间内对它们执行动画
Simple as that.
就这么简单
So here's what the method looks like.
这就是一个方法的样子
It's called animateWithDuration.
There's a few different kinds of it, but
this is the basic one.
这是最基础的
You can see that it takes a duration.
你可以看到它接受一个 duration
That's how long the animation is going to take.
这就是动画会执行的时长
A delay is wait.
delay 是等待
Should I wait to start this animation?
比如我是否应该等会执行这个动画
Options, we'll talk about those later.
Optinos，待会我们会说到这个
Then the block, okay?
然后是 block
Takes no arguments, returns no arguments there, that closure.
这个闭包没有参数，也不返回参数
That's where you're going to change those view properties.
这里就是你修改这些视图属性的地方
And it also has a completion closure.
然后它也有一个代表完成的闭包
When it's done animating, the animation actually completed,
当动画执行完成的时候，动画完全执行完毕
it will call this and it'll let you know whether
它就会调用这个，它会让你知道
the animation finished or whether it was interrupted by
动画是否执行完成了，还是被另一个
another animation that tried to change that same property.
尝试着修改同样属性的动画给中断了
Okay, because you can have multiple animations going off
因为你可以同时执行多个
at the same time.
动画
All right? So what does it look like to
这就是如何使用
call this?
调用这个
Here's an example.
这里是一个例子
So this is going to, two seconds from now,
它会从现在开始执行两秒
start fading my view out over three seconds.
从三秒钟淡出我的视图开始
And when it's done fading out,
当它完成淡出之后
it's going to remove it from the super view.
它就会把视图从父视图中移除
Okay? That's what this one
就只是这一行
line of code does, okay?
代码的作用
It's got, I guess it's more than one of code,
它有，好吧我猜不止一行代码
cuz you've got the closures in there.
因为这里有个闭包
But it's what it does, okay?
但它就是这样
So you can see here that I say I want three seconds, for
你可看到我写了我想要执行三秒
it to take three seconds, but
它就会执行三秒
I want it to start in two seconds, so
但我想要它在两秒钟后开始
you're going to take five seconds total.
所以这里一共是五秒
Okay, it's not going to do anything for the first two.
它在开头的两秒什么都不会做
And then in my block, I just change my alpha.
然后在 block 里面我修改了 alpha
Right? From 1, which it started out,
对吧，从1开始，
I have an if that says only do this if I'm fully opaque.
我需要它完全消失
So I just set it to zero.
所以我设置为0
That's all I have to do.
这就是全部了
And then in my completion block, if I finished,
然后在 completion block 里
that's the if $0, that's the finish thing.
如果完成了动画，if $0 这就是是否完成
If I finish,
如果完成了
then I'm going to remove myself from the super view.
那么从父视图中移除自己
But if someone else animated alpha in between,
但如果在某个地方有另一个操作 alpha 的动画
then I'm not going to remove myself from super view.
那么我就不应该移除自己了
Which makes sense, right?
很合理对吧
Because they probably changed the alpha to something
因为它们可能把 alpha 修改为
nonzero, okay?
非0的值了
Now, a very important thing to understand about animation,
现在，理解动画非常重要的是
all animation that's going on, is when you make changes,
所有的动画，当你修改的属性的时候
they happen immediately.
它们都是立即生效的
The animation is just showing it to the user over time.
动画只是用来给用户展示的
Okay? So in this code,
所以在这里代码里
when I print myView.alpha equals myView.alpha,
当我输出 myView.alpha 等于 myView.alpha
that is going to print zero, because that closure changed
它会打印0，因为在闭包中已经修改为
it to zero and it does it right away.
0了，所以它会立刻生效
Okay. Even though the user doesn't
即使用户还没有在屏幕上
get to see it on screen for five seconds,
看到五秒的动画
that's irrelevant.
这也并不重要
The fact is, I just changed my alpha to zero.
事实就是，我已经修改了 alpha 为 0
Okay. It's very important to
这对于理解来说非常重要
understand and it will take some wrapping your head around
可能会困扰你
until you really understand and work with it.
知道你完全明白它到底是怎么运作的了
But it's a little bit like multithreaded programming to
这就有点像多线程编程
understand.
明白了吗
But really,
但事实上
all animation is presenting it to the user over time.
所有的动画呈现给用户的时间
It's not changing it over time.
并不是真正修改其值的时间
Okay? All right.
好了
So that's it.
就是这样
That's how view animation works.
这就是视图动画的使用方法
Here's all the options.
现在来说说 options
There's billions of them here.
这里有数十亿个选项
You can change the curve.
你可以修改曲线
So CurseEaseInEaseOut means that it starts slowly and
比如 CurseEaseInEaseOut 的意思是一开始慢速
then speeds up to normal and then slows back down again.
然后加速到正常速度，最后又慢下来
So my fade, that's the way it worked.
比如我的淡出，它就会这样
It would start fading out slowly and
它会先淡出得很慢
then normal speed and then at the very end when it's fading
然后正常速度，然后在最后
out, fade out a little slower.
又淡出得慢一点
Okay?
You can also,
你也可以自己试
I don't have time to show you all these things, but
我没有时间来向你展示全部的效果
you can look at all these things.
但你可以自己试试
BeginFromCurrentState is an interesting one because I just
BeginFromCurrentState 是一个很有意思的东西
told you that the change happens immediately.
我刚才告诉你们，属性会立刻发生
But if you issued another animation that changed
但如果你又另一个动画也在改变
the alpha and you had this BeginFromCurrentState on,
alpha 然后你设置了 BeginFromCurrentState
then that animation would pick up wherever any other
那么动画会从你当前动画
animation is.
开始执行
So that other animation might be partway
所以其他的动画或许
through doing the alpha.
直接变化透明度
And then I do another animation with this
然后我使用另一个设置了 BeginFromCurrentState
BeginFromCurrentState and it's not going to start with it
它并不会从0开始变化
at zero, which is what alpha is now.
虽然现在属性的值就是0
It's going to pick up the partial, okay?
它会从当前部分开始
So that's one way where you can actually kind of over time
这也是一个你可以获取到当前值的方法
get the value, by issuing another animation.
通过另一个动画
Remember, all these animations are happening in another
记住，所有的动画都发生在另一个线程的
thread off the main queue.
而不是主队列
They're all happening out of time for you, okay?
执行的时间并不取决于你
When you send that last line of code,
当你执行到最后一行代码的时候
alpha immediately went to zero and you're on your way.
alpha 会立刻变为 0
Your code is still going.
你的代码也继续执行
The fact that things are happening on screen over time,
在屏幕上发生的一切会随着时间推移
it's kind of not relevant to you.
这和你没有什么关系
It's relevant to your user though.
这和你的用户有关系
Okay?
Sometimes you want to change an entire view and
有时你想要改变整个视图
you can do that as well.
你可以可以
I'll give you an example here of a playing card.
我们会给你一个例子展示如果改变 card
So if I had a playing card that has a back and a front.
如果我有前后两张卡
I might want to flip that card over.
我或许会想要反转卡牌
Okay, so I wanna change everything in the view.
所以我想要在视图中改变这一切
I wanna redraw the view basically, but
我想要重画这个视图
I want it to flip over.
我想要它翻转
I don't want it to just boop change,
我不想要它只是 BOOM 一下改变
I want it to have an animation where it flips over.
我想要有一个动画它可以翻转过来
So you can do flips over and curls up and dissolves, okay,
所以你可以翻转，卷曲和溶解
you can do all those.
你可以做这些操作
The way you do that is with a different UIView class
要做到这些你需要使用 UIView 的另一个类方法
method called transitionWithView.
叫做 transitionWithView
You just give it the view, the playing card view or whatever.
你给它一个视图，一张卡片或者其他的东西
You tell how long you want the animation to take.
你需要告诉它动画执行多久
What kind of thing you want like flipping or
你要想什么样的动画，是翻转还是
dissolving or whatever.
溶解还是其他什么
You give it the animation.
你可以让它执行动画
Inside that animation you're changing your view,
在动画中你要改变你的视图
changing the attributes in your view.
改变你视图的参数
Like, if you had your calculator and
比如你有你的计算器
you wanted to change from one graph to another.
你想要从一个图表修改为另一种
In here you would change the graph.
在这里你修改图表
Okay, you would change it so when it draws the next time,
好了，这样下一次它会绘图
we draw something different.
我们画一点不同的东西
And then it would animate it, dissolve it, or whatever and
然后它会执行动画，溶解或者其他的
show the new version.
然后展示新的样式
In this closure you're changing anything you want
在闭包中你要可以修改任何东西
about the view, any attributes, any properties.
关于视图的，任何属性，任何参数
So the next time it draws, it will draw differently and
这样下一次绘制的时候，它就会绘制另一种样子
then this animation will kind of interpolate between those
然后动画也会插入这两种状态
two states, doing a flip or dissolve or whatever.
比如翻转或者溶解或者其他
So that's another kind of thing.
这又是另一个东西了
Now this one you're probably going to be
这个你可能只有在家庭作业的
doing in your homework.
时候来做了
Okay, I think I asked you explicitly to do some sort of
我想我会让你明确地做一种
animation like this.
这样的动画效果
Either this one or the last one, either one.
这个或者上一个，两者之一
So yeah, here's the playing card example.
好了，这就是卡片动画的例子
You can see in the closure I'm just changing the card to
你可以看到闭包我
be face up.
连接了两张卡
And so the next time it draws,
这样下一次它开始绘制
it's going to draw differently.
它就会绘制另一种样式
Okay?
And again, this happens immediately.
再说一次，这个会立刻发生
That card is face up equals not card is face up.
面朝上的卡片等于没有面朝上的卡片
That happens instantly,
因为变化会立刻发生
as soon as I call this method, okay?
只要我调用了这个方法
It's just that over time, on screen, it will happen.
它会随着时间改变显示
But it happened immediately, right there.
但它是的变化是即刻的
If the next line, I say if card is face up,
如果下一行我写卡面朝上
it's going to be the changed value, okay?
它也会修改值
These transitionWithView methods,
这些 transitionWithViewAnimatedWithDuration
animated with duration, they return immediately.
它们是立刻返回的
They do what's in the enclosure and
它们执行闭包中的东西
return immediately.
并且立刻返回
Okay?
If you're animating changes to the view hierarchy,
如果想要你在视图层级中有任何动画的改变
like you're hiding views or
比如隐藏视图或者
removing them from super view and that's all you're doing,
从父类那里移除视图都可以
and you want them to flip over and
你想要翻转
go away, then you can use this transitionFromView to view.
然后离开，你可以用 transitionFromViewToView
Okay? Otherwise it's
除此之外
exactly the same.
其他都是一样的
It's just for things that change the view hierarchy but
它只是改变视图层级
it's basically the same.
但其他的都是一样的
So there's no closure there because
所以这里没有闭包
the change you're making is change in the view hierarchy.
是由于你改变的是视图层级
You're not changing card that's face up,
你不是在改变卡片是否面朝上
you're actually changing whether the view is
你在改变的是视图是否
in the hierarchy anymore.
仍然在层级中
Yeah. >> I'm just wondering, so.
>> 学生提问
If you want to specify several of the [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah.
好
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> Yeah.
>> No, they are.
That's a good question in this particular API.
对于这个特殊的 API 来说是个好问题
Ask me on Piazza and I'll try and
待会在走廊上来问我
some APIs you specify as an array, some APIs different.
我会试着用一些 API，一些 API 不同
It depends but most times, Swift is an eNom,
根据情况而定，但 Swift 是 enum
so you are doing something like that or combining them,
你可以这样做或者把它们结合起来
so ask me on Piazza.
待会下来问我
Okay.
So that's it for today.
这就是今天的全部内容
On Friday,
在周五
we have a great section which is UICollectionView.
我们会有一个很棒的部分关于 UICollectionView
It's great because UICollectionView is very
很棒是因为 UICollectionView 非常
similar to UITableView.
类似与 UITableView
You'll really understand UITableView
你会理解 UITableView 的
if you go do look at this UICollectionView one.
如果你看了这个 UICollectionView
Monday's a holiday and the next week I'm going to start
周一是节日，然后下周我会开始讲
on that physics-based animation.
基于物理的动画
>> [COUGH] >> Thank you very much.
>> 谢谢大家
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 想了解更多，请登录 stanford.edu